var quiz = [
{Question: "Question: What process is used to establish the automatic transport of data between the view controller's context-attributes and the UI element in its layout? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data binding"," Data migration"," Context mapping"," View assembly"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement is used to generically define the data reference variable z1? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" data z1 type ref to PA0001"," data z1 type any table"," data z1 type ref to data"," data z1 type any"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the event block that all of your code changes belongs to if you do not explicitly code any event blocks in an executable program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" INITIALIZATION"," START-OF-SELECTION"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"," LOAD-OF-PROGRAM"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: A view can only be displayed in which circumstances? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It cannot always be displayed."," It has been embedded in a window."," It can always be displayed."," It contains an inbound and outbound plug."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In which sequence are the following ABAP Events triggered? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1. INITIALIZATION 2. START-OF-SELECTION 3. AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," 1. START-OF-SELECTION 2. AT SELECTION-SCREEN 3. INITIALIZATION"," 1. INITIALIZATION 2. AT SELECTION-SCREEN 3. START-OF-SELECTION"," 1. AT SELECTION-SCREEN 2. INITIALIZATION 3. START-OF-SELECTION"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to define data structures to hold two fields with data elements s_carr_id and s_carrname. Which of the following�declarations can be used to define this data structure? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gty_flight"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," DATA: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does the lifetime of a component controller begin and end? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It ends the first time the Web�Dynpro�application is called at runtime and ends when the Web�Dynpro�application that called and�instantiated�the component ends."," It begins with the Web Dynpro component and ends with the Web Dynpro application that called it."," It lasts from creating data within the controller to cover the whole period during which the component is in use."," It begins the first time the Web Dynpro application is called at runtime and ends when the Web Dynpro application that called and instantiated the component ends."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the technical settings for a transparent table, buffering is switched on and single record buffering is selected. Which statement uses the buffered data assuming that the WHERE clause contains restrictions for all key fields? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT SINGLE � ."," SELECT � INTO TABLE � ."," SELECT � . ENDSELECT."," SELECT SINGLE � FOR UPDATE."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: The data buffered on each application server� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Is does not the same."," Is always the same."," Is never the same."," Depends on the users."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you declare an internal table using the transparent table A as its line type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA gt_itab TYPE TABLE OF a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE LINE OF a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE REF TO a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE a."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Function groups"," Executables"," Class pools"," Module pools"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In which controller type can you embed a service call? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Interface controller"," Configuration controller"," Component controller"," View controller"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What scheduling technique is used by the ABAP debugger dispatcher for processing user requests? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Multiple Queue"," First in , First out"," Shortest First"," Round Robin"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You Created the following ABAP Code: DATA x TYPE REF TO DATA, DATA y TYPE REF TO OBJECT, ASSIGN x TO <fs>, ASSIGN y TO <fs>. You want to add a declaration of <fs> to the Code. Which of the Following Declarations are Valid? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" FIELD-SYMBOLS TYPE REF TO DATA"," FIELD-SYMBOLS <fs> TYPE ANY�"," FIELD-SYMBOLS <fs>"," FIELD-SYMBOLS <fs> TYPE REF TO ANY"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When is a foreign key check performed on an input/output field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a append search is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a check table is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a value help is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a search is defined"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In an ABAP program you have the following code sequence: DATA var TYPE n LENGTH 1. FIELD �SYMBOLS <fs> TYPE c. ASSIGN var TO <fs> CASTING. Which type is used to cast the assigned memory area? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The type of <fs>"," The default type I"," The type of var"," The default type STRING"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Using the screen system table, what can you modify through a LOOP AT SCREEN � ENDLOOP construct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Screen status"," Function code of buttons"," Values of screen elements"," Attributes of screen elements"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" All standard SQL commands can be used"," Syntax is checked at design time"," The application server buffer is NOT used"," It can be used with any DBMS"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to develop a program that processes character type data. When you implement the program, you can either use the classical string statements or the newer strings expressions and functions. What are the main benefits of using string expressions and string functions? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You can write code that is very easy to read and understand"," You can improve the performance significantly"," You can write compact syntax instead of a long sequence of statements"," You can reduce the number of intermediate variables"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You create a domain in the ABAP dictionary. How can you use this domain? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" As the data type of an input field on a dialog screen"," As the data type of a data element in the ABAP Dictionary"," As the data type of a variable in an ABAP program"," As the data type of a selection screen field"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Can identify where program behavior may change"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"],correct:[0, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which database objects can you create in the ABAP Dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Foreign key relationships"," Logical databases"," Projection views"," Indexes"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement using the local type gty_1 correctly defines a data object? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA gv_1 TYPE gty_1."," DATA gv_1 TYPE gty_1 DEFAULT '1'."," DATA gv_1 LIKE gty_1."," CONSTANTS gc_1 TYPE gty_1 VALUE '1'."],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To reserve an area on the screen for an ALV Grid Control, you must do the following: Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"," Use the Screen Painter"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How is an ABAP program with several dialog steps executed? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The ABAP dispatcher takes over the entire execution without assigning any work process."," Usually, dialog steps are assigned to different dialog work processes."," The program is always executed in just one dialog work process without roll out"," The program is always executed in just one dialog work process with roll out."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: When would you call the RFC function module synchronously? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" During two-way communication"," During queue processing"," During unidirectional communication"," During interactive communication"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To create development classes"," To create lock objects"," To maintain program translations"," To activate logging for transparent tables"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following requirements can you implement a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A handler method for an event that has a returning parameter"," A factory method that returns an object reference"," A private static helper method that returns a single value as the result of an algorithm"," A method to set an instance attribute with one importing parameter and no other parameters"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which view types can you use to join two tables with an outer join? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Help view"," Database view"," Projection view"," Maintenance view"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you find customer exists in an ABAP program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search for �CALL CUSTOMER� in the program"," Search for �CL_EXTHANDLER� in the program."," Search for customer exists in the program documentation"," Search for customer exists in the Repository Information System"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You write a report that displays mass data in a table. You decide to use the ALV Grid control (class�CL_GUI_ALV_GRID) instead of a classical list display with WRITE statements. Which of the following functions can you offer to the user without doing any specific programming?There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Display details by double-clicking on a row"," Sort and filter the data by any column"," Change column width and sequence"," Convert currency amount columns"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement ends a screen sequence and starts from initial screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE SCREEN"," CALL SCREEN"," LEAVE TO SCREEN"," SET SCREEN 0"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following Data Types are allowed in ABAP? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DECFLOAT34"," DECFLOAT64"," DECFLOAT16"," DECFLOAT32"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be exposed in the component interface of a Web dynpro component? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Custom methods of the component controller"," Context nodes of WINDOW controllers"," Public attributes of WINDOW controllers"," Standard hook methods of the component controller"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have created a Web Dynpro view that shows data for airline connections between cities. You want to display flight data for a specific date in a different view after the user select a date and presses a button. Which of the following actions you must perform? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Edit the handler method in the view controller"," Create and link plugs between the views"," Add a client-side event in the view"," Set the interface property for key fields"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you create lock objects and lock modules for use in ABAP programs that access the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules and the lock objects"," Use the ABAP dictionary to create the lock objects. Use the function builder to create the lock modules"," Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules. The lock objects are created in the program logic"," Use the ABAP Dictionary to create the lock objects. The lock modules are created automatically"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to check the user input in the field FIELD_NAME on a classical screen. If an incorrect value is entered, the user should be able to correct the field value. How do you call the module CHECK_MODULE in the PAI of the screen to accomplish this? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" FIELD field_name MODULE check_module."," FIELD field_name MODULE check_module MESSAGE Ennn."," CHAIN. MODULE check_module FIELD field_name. ENDCHAIN."," MODULE check_module ON ERROR."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following must you do to be able to use a Business Add-in(BADI)? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Modify the adapter class"," Create the BADI implementation"," Write code for methods"," Activate the enhancement project"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you perform a syntax check on the program"," When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you save the program"," When you activate the program"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement must end with a period."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following items are used in a Web Dynpro Application to transport database data to the user interface? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Context node"," Inbound plug"," Interface controller"," Supply function"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Attachment to a field"," Fixed values"," Import / export parameters"," Selection method"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You can use the logical expression IS SUPPLIED for any formal parameter passed to which modularization unit? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subroutine (FORM routine)"," Instance method"," Static method"," Function module"],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you add fields to an SAP-delivered transparent table without modification? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the database utility to enhance the definition on the database directly."," Define a structure containing the new fields and include it in the table definition."," Add the new fields to the table definition."," Create an append structure containing the new fields."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CURR"," CUKY"," UNIT"," DEC"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search helps"," Maintenance screens"," Events"," Append searches"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to include an element of type �Table� in your web dynpro. What actions add the corresponding columns to the table automatically? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Include the method BIND_TABLE of IF_WD_CONTEXT_NODE."," Right click the table and select the �CREATE_BINDING� option"," Bind the table attribute �DATA_SOURCE� to the context node"," Generate a �BIND_TABLE� method using the web dynpro method wizard."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does SAP recommend that you use a full buffering type for a database table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When the table is small and seldom written"," When the table is large and frequently written"," When the table is small and frequently written"," When the table is large and seldom written"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you do with the code inspector? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Create only local inspections, objects sets and check variants"," Choose from only the performance, security and user interface check categories"," Create your own inspections, object sets and check variants"," Create an object set to represent the programs and objects to be inspected"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which class is used to define a reference for an instance of the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Class�CL_GUI_BDC_GRID"," Class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In addition to the primary key of an internal table, how many secondary indexes can you define for an internal table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 10"," 15"," 0"," 1"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following capabilities is provided by the Application Layer platform of SAP Netweaver? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Database and operating system abstraction"," Multi-channel access"," Master data management"," Business process management"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: When must a foreign key have domain equality? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" For a text table"," Never"," For a check field"," Always"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you change in the ABAP Debugger? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Definition of a structure"," Value of a reference variable"," Content of an internal table"," Value of a constant"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view uses an inner join in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Candidate key view"," Database view"," Maintenance view"," Help view"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Module pools"," Class pools"," Executables"," Function groups"],correct:[0, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which ABAP Dictionary definition can you assign fixed values? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Field of a transparent table"," Component of a structure"," Domain"," Data element"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following predefined ABAP types is incomplete? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" XSTRING"," F"," STRING"," P"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following enhancement options does not require any preparation from SAP? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Explicit enhancement point"," New BAdIs"," Implicit enhancement point"," Explicit enhancement sections"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements dynamically changes the data type of field z1? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Unassign <fs>"," Assign z1 to <fs>"," Move z1 to <fs>"," Assign z1 to <fs> casting"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In an ABAP program, you to assign an initial value to an elementary data object when you define it. Which addition must you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" OBLIGATORY"," VALUE"," READ-ONLY"," DEFAULT"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of creating a database view to implement a join, instead of formulating the join directly in an Open SQL SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" A database view can be reused in other programs"," A database view can be buffered"," An outer join can only be implemented in a database view"," A secondary index can be created for a database view"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You defined data reference z1 generically. Which statement would you use to access the content of the referenced variable? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Get reference of z1 into wa"," Assign z1->* to <fs>"," Assign (z1) to <fs>"," Assign z1 to <fs>"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to add a field type CURR to a transparent table. What else must you do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create a new field CUKY as a pre-defined type."," Create a reference to a field of type CUKY."," Add a check table that contains a field of type CUKY."," Add a key fieldof type CUKY."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you maintain documentation for input fields on your screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS AFTER INPUT (PAI)."," Define text tables for the underlying structure."," Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT (PBO)."," Add documentation to the underlying data element."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to loop over an internal table without copying each table row to a work area. How can you achieve this using a field symbol? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LOOP AT <itab> TRANSPORTING INTO <field_symbol>. ENDLOOP."," LOOP AT <itab> INTO <field_symbol>. ENDLOOP."," LOOP AT <itab> REFERENCE INTO <field_symbol>. ENDLOOP."," LOOP AT <itab> ASSIGNING <field_symbol>. ENDLOOP."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your code contains the following statement: READ TABLE gt_itab INTO gs_struc INDEX 1. When defining gt_itab, which internal table types can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Standard and sorted"," Standard and hashed"," Sorted and hashed"," Standard, sorted, and hashed"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How is an ABAP program with several dialog steps executed? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The program is always executed in just one dialog work process without roll out"," The ABAP dispatcher takes over the entire execution without assigning any work process."," Usually, dialog steps are assigned to different dialog work processes."," The program is always executed in just one dialog work process with roll out."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: An ABAP program processes the following expression: r = a / b + c. Which of the following data declarations would cause the runtime environment to use fixed-point arithmetic for the above expression? There are 2 correct answers to this question. Note: Answers of this question are not verified by our experts, please study yourself and select the appropriate answers. ",Response: [" DATA: r TYPE f, a TYPE i VALUE 201, b TYPE i VALUE 200, c TYPE f."," DATA: r TYPE p, a type I VALUE 201, b type I VALUE 200, c type i."," DATA: r TYPE p DECMALS 2, a TYPE i VLAUE 201, b TYPE i VALUE 200, c TYPE f."," DATA: r TYPE p DECIMALS 2, a TYPE i VALUE 201, b TYPE i VALUE 200, c TYPE"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the declarative statements used to define the selection? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" PARAMETERS"," SELECT-OPTIONS"," SELECTION-SCREEN"," None of the above"],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What type of ABAP Dictionary view is implemented as an INNER JOIN? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Projection view"," Help view"," Maintenance view"," Database view"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: A transport company keeps track of this availability in two tables, table VEHICLES and table TRANSPORT. To accept a new transport of a certain capacity must be found in table VEHICLES. If a record is found, a record is created in table TRANSPORT. The capacity is then adjusted in table VEHICLES. You have four function modules at your disposal. UPD_VEHI_A and UPD_VEHI_B update a matching report in table VEHICLES. If an error occurs both issue a message of type X. If no error occurs only UPD_VEHI_A issues a message of type X. If no error occurs UPD_VEHI_A issues a message of type I. UPD_TRAN_A and UPD_TRAN_B create a single record in table TRANSPORT. If an error occurs both issues a message of type X. If no error occurs only UPD_TRAN_A issues a message of type I. Which of the following function module calls ensures a single logical unit of work? ",Response: [" 1.UPD_VEHI_A  2.UPD_TRAN_A"," 1. UPD_TRAN_B  2. UPD_VEHI_B"," 1. UPD_TRAN_A  2. UPD_VEHI_B"," 1.UPD_VEHI_A  2.UPD_TRAN_B"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In addition to the primary key of an internal table, how many secondary indexes can you define for an internal table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 15"," 10"," 0"," 1"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The superclass method is an instance method"," The super class method is abstract"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"," The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement using the local type gty_1 correctly defines a data object? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA gv_1 LIKE gty_1."," CONSTANTS gc_1 TYPE gty_1 VALUE '1'."," DATA gv_1 TYPE gty_1."," DATA gv_1 TYPE gty_1 DEFAULT '1'."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you improve the performance when accessing a large data volume database table? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define appropriate indexes for the database table."," Apply the appropriate data class and size category."," Switch the database table to fully buffered."," Change the table type in the dictionary"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to translate dynamic text in a web dynpro. From which abstract class should you inherit? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CL_WD_COMPONENT_ASSISTANCE"," CL_WD_CONFIGURATION_MODEL"," CL_WD_CONTEXT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_COMPONENT_SERVICES"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to define data structures to hold two fields with data elements s_carr_id and s_carrname. Which of the following�declarations can be used to define this data structure? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," DATA: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gty_flight"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is mandatory for automatic data transport between a variable and an input field on a classical screen (dynpro)? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The variable must be declared using the DATA statement."," The property OUTPUT of the input field must be set."," The name of the variable and the name of the input field must be identical."," The variable must be declared using the TABLES statement."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which hook method exists for all controller types? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" wddoonopen( )"," wddobeforenavigation( )"," wddoinit( )"," wddoonclose( )"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(1) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."," The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," Field labels are defined for the domain."," Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You build a dialog screen with an input field in an ABAP program. How do you ensure that the contents of the screen field can be accessed in the program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Enter the name of a data object in the Paramter ID attribute of the screen field"," Define a data object in the program with the same name as the screen field"," Use a MOVE statement in a PAI module to copy the data to a data object"," Use the GET statement in the program to transport the data from the screen field"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 100"," 1�65535"," 10"," 1"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CUKY"," UNIT"," DEC"," CURR"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," SUBMIT"," CALL TRANSACTION"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Identify the ways to map context structures.� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Dynamic context mapping"," External context mapping"," Static context mapping"," Direct context mapping"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What happens when an authorization check fails? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The program is terminated."," A type E message is displayed."," The system field SY-SUBRC is set to a value other than zero."," A CX_AUTH_FAILED type exception is raised."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search helps"," Append searches"," Events"," Maintenance screens"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have defined a classical screen (dynpro) with mandatory input fields. You want to exit the screen using the Cancel button even if not all of the mandatory fields have been filled. What is necessary to achieve this? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Assign function type E to the Cancel button and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."," Use the LOOP AT SCREEN. ... ENDLOOP statement to set the 'required' property of the input fields to zero."," Set the function type assigned to the Cancel button to S and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."," Set the function code assigned to the Cancel button to CANCEL and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"," SELECT-OPTIONS"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"," PARAMETERS"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A group of classes that apply Grid as a whole and inherit from a multiple class"," A group of classes that describe the BDC�Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of hierarchal classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole but do not inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following Data Types are allowed in ABAP? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DECFLOAT64"," DECFLOAT16"," DECFLOAT34"," DECFLOAT32"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Static attributes cannot be changed by an object."," Static attributes can be declared only in the private visibility section of the class."," Static attributes are declared with the CLASS-DATA statement."," A static attribute is the same across all instances of the class. There is only one static attribute across all instances of the class."],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you activate the program"," When you perform a syntax check on the program"," When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you save the program"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is data binding? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Connecting the values of user interface elements to the context attributes of the corresponding controller"," Connecting one Web Dynpro component to another Web Dynpro component"," Connecting a context node in one controller to a context node in another controller"," Connecting an outbound plug on one view to the inbound plug of another view"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following items are used in a Web Dynpro Application to transport database data to the user interface? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Inbound plug"," Supply function"," Interface controller"," Context node"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: If you are using external debugging (debugging of HTTP and RFC requests,�which arrive in your ABAP system), what will the Debugger do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Never stop; external breakpoints operate on users other than your own."," May or may not stop, depending on external factors."," Always stop when the external breakpoint is reached."," Do not stop when the external breakpoint is reached."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view cannot be used in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Maintenance view"," Database view"," Help view"," Candidates key view"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: To benefit from the hash algorithm when accessing a hashed internal table, how do you specify the key? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Any key"," Under-qualified"," Left aligned, gap free"," Fully qualified"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you embed a subscreen in a main screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use SET SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to select all the records from a database table where field CITY contains substring �BU� in any position. Which WHERE clause can you use in an Open SQL select statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" WHERE city LIKE �%BU*�"," WHERE city LIKE �_BU�"," WHERE city LIKE �%BU%�"," WHERE city LIKE �*BU*�"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Private event and private handler"," Public event and protected handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Private event and public handler"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You define a generic variable that can hold the ABAP types C, D, N, STRING, and T. You want to restrict the use of other ABAP types. Which generic data type must you use in the definition? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA"," CSEQUENCE"," CLIKE"," SIMPLE"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your colleague has asked you to analyze and ABAP program that does not behave correctly when a button is pressed on the initial screen. You want to start Debugger when the button is pressed so that you can perform your analysis. What do you type in the command field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" /h"," /hx"," /n"," Jdbg"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which property of the InputField UI element must be bound to a context attribute? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" enable"," value"," state"," visible"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your selection screen can be modified at which event? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," None of the above"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN ON <field_name>"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When are the changes to the VB* table transferred to the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When an update function module is executed"," When the enqueue work process is executed"," When the main program is executed"," When the update work process is executed"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you find customer exists in an ABAP program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search for customer exists in the Repository Information System"," Search for �CALL CUSTOMER� in the program"," Search for �CL_EXTHANDLER� in the program."," Search for customer exists in the program documentation"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Call the BAdI"," Define an interface for the BAdI."," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you do with the code inspector? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Create your own inspections, object sets and check variants"," Create an object set to represent the programs and objects to be inspected"," Choose from only the performance, security and user interface check categories"," Create only local inspections, objects sets and check variants"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the predefined reference variable used in ABAP OO to address the object itself? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUPER"," THIS"," SELF"," ME"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Global data types defined in SAP systems are� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data defined in the program that is visible to all the routines/statements within the ABAP program."," ABAP Dictionary types."," Date types does not defined Dictionary types."," Date types defined in the program using ABAP Dictionary types."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The application server buffer is NOT used"," Syntax is checked at design time"," All standard SQL commands can be used"," It can be used with any DBMS"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1"," 100"," 10"," 1�65535"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can only specify default values for the LOW and HIGH fields of the SELECT-OPTIONS input field."," The structure of the selection table created with SELECT-OPTIONS has four components: SIGN, OPTION, LOW, and HIGH."," You can use the addition NO-DISPLAY to hide the input field on the selection screen."," The SELECT-OPTIONS statement creates an internal table with a header line. The internal table is also known as the selection table."],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To create development classes"," To activate logging for transparent tables"," To create lock objects"," To maintain program translations"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUBMIT"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," CALL TRANSACTION"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP statements throws an error at the syntax check? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA variable"," DATA variable(5) TYPE t."," DATA variable(5) TYPE p."," DATA variable(5) TYPE n."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which property of the InputField UI element must be bound to a context attribute? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" state"," value"," enable"," visible"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In which database table type is there a one-to-one relationship between the Dictionary table definition and the relevant physical table in the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Internal table"," Cluster table"," Pooled table"," Transparent table"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your task is to enhance the screen of an SAP standard application. How do you determine if there is a customer exit for this task? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" You search in the flow logic of the screen for CAL CUSTOMER-SUBSCREEN statement"," You search in the SAP reference Implementation Guide (IMG) for a suitable user exit"," You search in the source code of the application for GET BADI statement"," You use the BAdI Builder (transaction SE19) to check for a suitable Business Add-In(BAdI)"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" They facilitate multilingual functionality"," They are easier to maintain than literals"," Then can store up to 256 characters"," The same text symbol can be used by other programs"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Selection method"," Attachment to a field"," Fixed values"," Import / export parameters"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."," Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: When do you need to use the GROUP BY clause in the SELECT statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If you want to use aggregate functions and at least one component in the field list is a column identifier"," If you want to use aggregate functions and all components in the field list are aggregate functions"," If you want to use ORDER BY to specify a sub-order"," If you want to redefine the sequence of the columns in the result set"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LxxxxO01"," LxxxxUXX"," LxxxxF01"," LxxxxTOP"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following rules must you follow when creating subscreens? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subscreens can call other subscreens."," Subscreens CANNOT have a field of type OK."," Subscreens can have a dialog module containing SET PF-STATUS."," Subscreens CANNOT have an AT EXIT-COMMAND module."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the CALL CUSTOMER-FUNCTION 'nnn' statement, nnn is a three-digit number�used in SAP programs for which of the following types of enhancement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" User exits"," New BAdIs"," Business add-ins"," Customer exits"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following requirements can you implement a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A handler method for an event that has a returning parameter"," A method to set an instance attribute with one importing parameter and no other parameters"," A private static helper method that returns a single value as the result of an algorithm"," A factory method that returns an object reference"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following enhancement options does not require any preparation from SAP? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Explicit enhancement sections"," Implicit enhancement point"," Explicit enhancement point"," New BAdIs"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: The data buffered on each application server� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Depends on the users."," Is always the same."," Is does not the same."," Is never the same."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you define data types that can be accessed directly by all ABAp repository objects in an SAP system? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" In a function module"," In a global class"," In the ABAP dictionary"," In a method"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: In an ABAP program, you to assign an initial value to an elementary data object when you define it. Which addition must you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" OBLIGATORY"," VALUE"," DEFAULT"," READ-ONLY"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."," Call the BAdI"," Define an interface for the BAdI."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid control level changes within a loop over an internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" LAST"," COLLECT"," END of <f>"," SUM"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have 2 objects: O1 of type class C1 and O2 of type class C2. Class C2 is a subclass of class C1. Which of the following statements implements an up cast? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" O2 ?= O1."," O1 = O2."," MOVE O1 TO O2."," MOVE O1 ?TO O2."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Execute command /h"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You write a program that updates a data record in the data base using the following statement: UPDATE scar FROM Is_scarr. Which of the following tasks does the Database Interface perform? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" It restricts the access to the log-on client"," It translates the statement to native SQL"," It checks the authorization of the current user"," It applies a logical lock to the updated data record."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following items are used in a Web Dynpro Application to transport database data to the user interface? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Inbound plug"," Context node"," Supply function"," Interface controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the result of the following arithmetic operation? DATA: intTYPEI. int=5*(3/10).Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1.5"," 0"," 2"," 1"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you maintain documentation for input fields on your screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT (PBO)."," Define text tables for the underlying structure."," Add documentation to the underlying data element."," Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS AFTER INPUT (PAI)."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: dbtab is a transparent table. What is declared by the following statement? DATA myvar TYPE dbtab. Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A reference to an internal table"," A structure variable"," An internal table"," An elementary field"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to add a field ZZPRICE to the SAP standard transparent table EKKO. Which of the following actions result in an enhancement of the SAP standard? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Insert ZZPRICE into an SAP structure for the table"," Add ZZPRICE to the customizing include for the table"," Insert ZZPRICE at the end of the table"," Create an append structure and add ZZPRICE to it."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following controller types can exist only once in a Web Dynpro component? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" View controller"," Component controller"," Window controller"," Configuration controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to add a field type CURR to a transparent table. What else must you do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create a reference to a field of type CUKY."," Add a check table that contains a field of type CUKY."," Create a new field CUKY as a pre-defined type."," Add a key fieldof type CUKY."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are asked to enhance the GUI status of an SAP standard application�How do you identify which menu exit function code you can use? Please choose the correct answer. Note: Answers of this question are not verified by our experts, please study yourself and select the appropriate answers. ",Response: [" It start with a plus (+)"," It starts with an ampersand (&)"," It starts with a dollar($)"," It starts with an asterisk (*)"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is an implicit enhancement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Overwrite method"," Pre-method"," Protected method"," Private method"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the root class in the RTTS inheritance tree? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CL_ABAP_DATADESCR"," CL_ABAP_TYPEDESCR"," CL_ABAP_ELEMDESCR"," CL_ABAP_COMPLEXDESCR"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be exposed in the component interface of a Web dynpro component? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Standard hook methods of the component controller"," Custom methods of the component controller"," Context nodes of WINDOW controllers"," Public attributes of WINDOW controllers"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You write the following ABAp statement: SELECT SINGLE carrid connid cityfrom cityto From spfli INTO gs_spfli WHERE carrid = pa_car AND connid = pa_con How are the fields in the field list of the SELECT statement copied to the target structure gs_spfli? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" They are copied from left to right"," They are copied from right to left"," They are copied to fields with the same name"," They are copied to fields with the same type"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which rules do you have to consider when working with pooled tables? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" An append structure can be created"," Only key fields should be used in WHERE condition"," All fields can be used in indexes"," Only key fields should be used in ORDER BY clauses"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" It can be used with any DBMS"," Syntax is checked at design time"," The application server buffer is NOT used"," All standard SQL commands can be used"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What happens when an authorization check fails? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A type E message is displayed."," A CX_AUTH_FAILED type exception is raised."," The system field SY-SUBRC is set to a value other than zero."," The program is terminated."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: With what can you simulate multiple inheritance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REDEFINITION"," CLASS CATEGORY"," INHERITING FROM"," INTERFACES"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You call a lock module�Which exceptions could the lock module raise when a logical lock CANNOT be set? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" CX_SY_DATA_ACCESS_ERROR"," SYSTEM_FAILURE"," FOREIGN_LOCK"," CX_SY_OPEN_SQL_ERROR"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: A structure has enhancement category 3, can be enhanced (character-type). Which set of elementary types is allowed for the new fields? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" C,D,N,T"," F,I,P,X"," D,I,string, T"," C,D,N,X"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You need to perform a downcast. What should you do? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Assign a subclass reference to a superclass reference."," Perform the downcast only if an upcast has already been done for the object reference."," Catch the exception CX_SY_MOVE_CAST_ERROR."," Use the operator �=�."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you improve the performance when accessing a large data volume database table? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define appropriate indexes for the database table."," Switch the database table to fully buffered."," Change the table type in the dictionary"," Apply the appropriate data class and size category."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following predefined ABAP types is incomplete? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" P"," XSTRING"," STRING"," F"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What options do you have when setting a watchpoint? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Stop at any change of all variables."," Stop at predefined conditions for a specific variable."," Stop at predefined conditions for all variables."," Stop at any change of a specific variable."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When must a foreign key have domain equality? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Never"," For a text table"," For a check field"," Always"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How would you define a method of an ABAP class to prevent this method from being available in a subclass? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Protected"," Private"," Final"," Abstract"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What type of method is generated automatically by the Web Dynpro Explorer when you assign an action to a button�UI element? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Ordinary method"," Event handler method"," Standard hook method"," Supply function"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the correct order for using a lock object? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Set the lock, read the data, release the lock, change the data"," Set the lock, read the data, change the data, release the lock"," Read the data, set the lock, change the data, release the lock"," release the lock, Read the data, set the lock, change the data"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which ABAP Dictionary definition can you assign fixed values? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Field of a transparent table"," Data element"," Domain"," Component of a structure"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you have to take into account before you decide to buffer a table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The entire table content must be loaded into the table buffer"," The database server must allow table buffering"," The data must always be read from the buffer"," The data read from the buffer may NOT be current"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which rules do you have to consider when working with pooled tables? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Only key fields should be used in WHERE condition"," All fields can be used in indexes"," An append structure can be created"," Only key fields should be used in ORDER BY clauses"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the Refactoring Assistant allow you to do? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Move between classes and interfaces"," Rename all subclasses of a method"," Rename all occurrences of a method"," Move components between superclasses and subclasses"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: With what can you simulate multiple inheritance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" INTERFACES"," CLASS CATEGORY"," REDEFINITION"," INHERITING FROM"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following predefined ABAP types is incomplete? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" P"," STRING"," F"," XSTRING"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An enhancement spot can contain an explicit enhancement point and an enhancement section."," An enhancement spot can contain an explicit enhancement point, explicit enhancement section, and new BAdI."," An enhancement spot can contain either an explicit enhancement point and enhancement section or a new BAdI only, but all three cannot be in the same enhancement spot."," An enhancement spot can contain one or more simple or composite enhancements."],correct:[0, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you embed a subscreen in a main screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use CALL SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are incorrect statements? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" TYPES: date_ty TYPE D LENGTH 10."," TYPES: Str TYPE STRING LENGTH 20."," TYPES: werks TYPE C LENGTH 4."," TYPES: carrid_ty LIKE spfli-s-carr_id."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following types of SQL statements always bypass the SAP table buffers? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" SELECT � INNER JOIN�"," SELECT SINGLE"," SELECT SUM (sales)"," SELECT � UP TO 1 ROW"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When would you call the RFC function module synchronously? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" During interactive communication"," During queue processing"," During unidirectional communication"," During two-way communication"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When do you need to use the GROUP BY clause in the SELECT statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If you want to use aggregate functions and at least one component in the field list is a column identifier"," If you want to use ORDER BY to specify a sub-order"," If you want to use aggregate functions and all components in the field list are aggregate functions"," If you want to redefine the sequence of the columns in the result set"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following tasks does the BADI implementing class perform? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Filtering"," Inserting"," Sequencing"," Deleting"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You create a domain in the ABAP dictionary. How can you use this domain? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" As the data type of a variable in an ABAP program"," As the data type of an input field on a dialog screen"," As the data type of a data element in the ABAP Dictionary"," As the data type of a selection screen field"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How would you find out if an application program offers a program exit? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" Use the Repository Information System"," Search for the character string CUSTOMER-FUNCTION"," Look for a customer exit in the SAP reference IMG within an application area"," Use the Application Hierarchy"],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do global types and local types have in common? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Search help"," Documentation"," Technical information"," Field labels"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of transport task is used when you modify SAP standard objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Transport of copies"," Workbench"," Development/Correction"," Repair"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions can you use to define transparent tables? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SE38"," SE16N"," SE11"," SM37"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be exposed in the component interface of a Web dynpro component? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Standard hook methods of the component controller"," Context nodes of WINDOW controllers"," Custom methods of the component controller"," Public attributes of WINDOW controllers"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following Data Types are allowed in ABAP? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DECFLOAT32"," DECFLOAT64"," DECFLOAT16"," DECFLOAT34"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to define data structures to hold two fields with data elements s_carr_id and s_carrname. Which of the following�declarations can be used to define this data structure? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gty_flight"," DATA BEGIN OF gs_flight,"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What must you specify in a Unicode system when opening a file in TEXT MODE? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The byte order"," The code page"," The ENCODING addition"," The Layer page"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"," The superclass method is an instance method"," The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"," The super class method is abstract"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What options do you have when setting a watchpoint? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Stop at predefined conditions for a specific variable."," Stop at any change of all variables."," Stop at predefined conditions for all variables."," Stop at any change of a specific variable."],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: SAP enhancements for customer exits are managed by which transaction? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Neither transaction listed here"," Transaction SMOD"," Application�CMOD"," Transaction CMOD"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: The software component for a customer package can be... Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" HOME"," Application Layer"," Any SAP software component (i.e., SAP_APPL, SAP_BASIS, SAP_HR, etc.)"," Database layer"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The structure of the selection table created with SELECT-OPTIONS has four components: SIGN, OPTION, LOW, and HIGH."," You can use the addition NO-DISPLAY to hide the input field on the selection screen."," The SELECT-OPTIONS statement creates an internal table with a header line. The internal table is also known as the selection table."," You can only specify default values for the LOW and HIGH fields of the SELECT-OPTIONS input field."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you use to achieve polymorphism? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Reports"," Inheritance"," Subroutines"," Events"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search helps"," Maintenance screens"," Append searches"," Events"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you define local classes in ABAP, which syntactical sequence must you follow? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The order doesn�t matter."," PUBLIC SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PRIVATE SECTION"," PRIVATE SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PUBLIC SECTION"," The order is handled automatically."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How many kinds of internal tables are supported in the ABAP language? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1"," 3"," 5"," 2"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your selection screen can be modified at which event? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," None of the above"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN ON <field_name>"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following function types in a GUI status are reserved for internal use? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" T-TRANSACTION"," S- SYSTEM"," E-EXIT"," H-HELP REQUEST"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you define data types that can be accessed directly by all ABAp repository objects in an SAP system? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" In the ABAP dictionary"," In a method"," In a function module"," In a global class"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which you should specify in a non-Unicode system when opening a file in TEXT MODE? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The code page"," The byte order"," The storage order"," The ENCODING addition"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Global data types defined in SAP systems are� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data defined in the program that is visible to all the routines/statements within the ABAP program."," Date types defined in the program using ABAP Dictionary types."," ABAP Dictionary types."," Date types does not defined Dictionary types."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following characters is the first of a menu exit function code? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" *"," -"," +"," &"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following values are replaceable in debugger mode? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Variables"," Table names"," Field names"," Constants"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Cannot be enforced"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" PARAMETERS"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"," SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"," SELECT-OPTIONS"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which method of passing parameters is preferred for its performance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Pass by reference"," Pass by value"," Pass by class"," Pass by subclass"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you maintain documentation for input fields on your screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS AFTER INPUT (PAI)."," Add documentation to the underlying data element."," Define text tables for the underlying structure."," Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT (PBO)."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."," Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to add a field type CURR to a transparent table. What else must you do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add a check table that contains a field of type CUKY."," Create a new field CUKY as a pre-defined type."," Add a key fieldof type CUKY."," Create a reference to a field of type CUKY."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following requirements can you implement a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A private static helper method that returns a single value as the result of an algorithm"," A handler method for an event that has a returning parameter"," A method to set an instance attribute with one importing parameter and no other parameters"," A factory method that returns an object reference"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: At most, how many menu items (including functions, separators and sub- menus) can a menu have on the screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above"," 15"," 20"," 10"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following standard types is numeric? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Decfloat32"," I"," P"," F"],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which SELECT statement will always bypass the SAP table buffers? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � INTO TABLE �"," SELECT � ENDSELECT."," SELECT � FOR UPDATE �"," SELECT � SINGLE �"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1�65535"," 1"," 10"," 100"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the difference between SAP Basis and SAP NetWeaver? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" All versions of SAP NetWeaver require the use of Unicode."," All versions of SAP NetWeaver include the ability to handle HTTP requests."," All versions of SAP�NetWeaver�require the use of�UTF-8."," There is no difference; the name change was driven by marketing alone."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the prerequisites when creating an append structure for a standard SAP table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The table cannot have any fields of type FLTP"," The enhancement category of the table is NOT set to �Not enhacable�"," The fields in the append structure should star with YY or ZZ"," The table must be copied before the append structure can be created"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When do you need to use the GROUP BY clause in the SELECT statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If you want to use aggregate functions and all components in the field list are aggregate functions"," If you want to use ORDER BY to specify a sub-order"," If you want to redefine the sequence of the columns in the result set"," If you want to use aggregate functions and at least one component in the field list is a column identifier"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is variable-length structure called? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Nested structure"," Nested link structure"," Link structure"," Flat structure"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Then can store up to 256 characters"," They are easier to maintain than literals"," The same text symbol can be used by other programs"," They facilitate multilingual functionality"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: A view can only be displayed in which circumstances? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It cannot always be displayed."," It has been embedded in a window."," It contains an inbound and outbound plug."," It can always be displayed."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which assignment will lead to a conversion error? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A type C data object with the value '1.50E4' to a type I data object DATA.gv_c(6) TYPE c VALUE '1.50E4', gv_i TYPE i. gv_i = gv_c."," An XSTRING type data object to a STRING type data object DATA.gv_xstring TYPE xstring, gv_string TYPE string. gv_xstring = 'AF00'. gv_string = gv_xstring."," A type C data object with the value '123' to a type C data object with length 2 DATA.gv_c3(3) TYPE c VALUE '123', gv_c2(2) TYPE c. gv_c2 = gv_c3."," A type P data object to a type F data object DATA.gv_p TYPE p VALUE '15000', gv_f TYPE f. gv_f = gv_p."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do global types and local types have in common? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Search help"," Technical information"," Documentation"," Field labels"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which view types can you use to join two tables with an outer join? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Projection view"," Help view"," Maintenance view"," Database view"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the declarative statements used to define the selection? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" PARAMETERS"," None of the above"," SELECTION-SCREEN"," SELECT-OPTIONS"],correct:[0, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You created a transparent table and during activation got a warning message 'Enhancement category for table missing'. What do you have to do to eliminate the warning message? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Provide the correct reference field for the Currency or Quantity field."," Select the option Not Classified from the enhancement category."," Select any option other than Not Classified from the enhancement category"," Change the Data Class and Size category in the technical settings."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: There are ____ versions of the ABAP Editor. Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 3"," 4"," 2"," 1"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You use Unified Modelling language (UML) to design your classes. You want to describe the message exchange between objects. Which diagram can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Sequence diagram"," Class diagram"," Component diagram"," Object diagram"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search helps"," Maintenance screens"," Append searches"," Events"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: With what can you simulate multiple inheritance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" INHERITING FROM"," REDEFINITION"," INTERFACES"," CLASS CATEGORY"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When starting the Debugger, what circumstance causes the runtime error�DEBUGGING_NOT_POSSIBLE? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When more than five sessions are already associated with this login user"," When more than six sessions are already associated with this login user"," When the number of debugging sessions on the server exceeds the value defined by the profile parameter rdisp/wpdbug_max_no"," Starting a non-exclusive mode in a productive system"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which context object is the attribute LEAD_SELECTION_INDEX related? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Node"," Supply function"," Element"," Attribute"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you create lock objects and lock modules for use in ABAP programs that access the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the ABAP dictionary to create the lock objects. Use the function builder to create the lock modules"," Use the ABAP Dictionary to create the lock objects. The lock modules are created automatically"," Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules and the lock objects"," Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules. The lock objects are created in the program logic"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which rules do you have to consider when working with pooled tables? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Only key fields should be used in WHERE condition"," An append structure can be created"," All fields can be used in indexes"," Only key fields should be used in ORDER BY clauses"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You can resort the table with SORT"," You need to specify a key in the table declaration"," You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"," You can read the records by index or key"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(1) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."," Field labels are defined for the domain."," The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."],correct:[0, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: For a given date(variable lv_date), you want to find all the connections from Frankfurt to Sydney with exactly one stopover. You want to fly from the stopover city to Sydney on the same day you arrive in the stopover city. Table ZFLIGHTS hold the following information about flights. -flightid: primary key -cityfrom:departure city -datefrom: departure date -timefrom:departure time -cityto:destination city -dateto:destination date -timeto:destination time Which of the following Open SQL Queries can you use to find all the possible stopover cities? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT cityfrom INTO TABLE lt_cities FROM zflights AS destination WHERE cityto IN (SELECT DISTINCT cityfrom FROM zflights WHERE dateto = destination~datefrom AND timeto < destination~timefrom AND cityfrom = �FRANKFURT� AND datefrom = lv_date ) AND destination~cityto = �Sydney�"," SELECT DISTINCT cityto INTO TABLE lt_cities FROM zflights AS destination WHERE cityfrom IN (SELECT cityto FROM zflights WHERE dateto = destination~datefrom AND timeto < destination~timefrom AND cityfrom = �FRANKFURT� AND datefrom = lv_date ) AND destination~cityto = �Sydney�"," SELECT DISTINCT cityfrom INTO TABLE lt_cities FROM zflights AS destination WHERE cityfrom IN (SELECT cityto FROM zflights WHERE dateto = destination~datefrom AND timeto < destination~timefrom AND cityfrom = �FRANKFURT� AND datefrom = lv_date ) AND destination~cityto = �Sydney�"," SELECT cityto INTO TABLE lt_cities FROM zflights AS destination WHERE cityfrom IN (SELECT DISTINCT cityto FROM zflights WHERE dateto = destination~datefrom AND timeto < destination~timefrom AND cityfrom = �FRANKFURT� AND datefrom = lv_date ) AND destination~cityto = �Sydney�"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following enhancement options does not require any preparation from SAP? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Explicit enhancement sections"," Implicit enhancement point"," Explicit enhancement point"," New BAdIs"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: A screen has the following PAI flow logic: PROCESS AFTER INPUT FIELD A MODULE check_A FIELD A MODULE check_B CHAIN. FIELD:C,D MODULE check_CD ENDCHAIN FIELD:C,B. MODULE check_CB ENDCHAIN What happens if the application senda a type E message during the check_CB module processing? Please choose the correct answer. Note: Answers of this question are not verified by our experts, please study yourself and select the appropriate answers. ",Response: [" The screen is displayed again and the PBO flow logic is processed. Only fields B and C are ready for input."," The screen is displayed again without processing the PBO flow logic. All fields are ready for input."," The screen is NOT displayed again. Processing terminates and the user must restart the ABAP program"," The screen is displayed again without processing the PBO logic flow. Only fields B and C are ready for input"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a program that uses ABAP class. Which components of the class can you create directly from the program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Only public components"," All components"," Only protected components"," Only private components"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A database view is implemented as an outer join."," A maintenance view is implemented as an outer join."," A database view is implemented as an inner join."," A maintenance view is implemented as an inner join."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: can you search for suitable classic Business Add-Ins(BAdIs)? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Search in an application program for the method GET_INSTANCE of class CL_EXITHANDLER"," Search in the Repository Information System and choose Enhancements - >Customer Exits"," Search for suitable entries in the relevant component in the Implementation Guide (IMG)"," Use the SAP menu Tools -> ABAP Workbench -> Development -> Business Object Builder"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Call the BAdI"," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."," Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Define an interface for the BAdI."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which class is used to define a reference for an instance of the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Class�CL_GUI_BDC_GRID"," Class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the maximum number of watchpoints that can exist at one time? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 10"," No limit"," 8"," 6"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You need to create a piece of code that can be used by multiple programs. Which of the following techniques for modularization does SAP recommend? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" A function module in a function group"," A method in a local class"," A method in a global class"," A subroutine in a program"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You write the following ABAp statement: SELECT SINGLE carrid connid cityfrom cityto From spfli INTO gs_spfli WHERE carrid = pa_car AND connid = pa_con  How are the fields in the field list of the SELECT statement copied to the target structure gs_spfli? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" They are copied from right to left"," They are copied from left to right"," They are copied to fields with the same name"," They are copied to fields with the same type"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you need to consider when creating a secondary index on a table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The most frequently selected fields should be at the first positions in the index"," The table will be updated more quickly if you create more indexes"," The index must always be unique"," The index can be created for specific database systems only"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What type of ABAP Dictionary view is implemented as an INNER JOIN? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Database view"," Help view"," Projection view"," Maintenance view"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Each statement must end with a period."," Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following characters is the first of a menu exit function code? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" +"," &"," *"," -"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does SAP recommend that you use a full buffering type for a database table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When the table is large and seldom written"," When the table is large and frequently written"," When the table is small and frequently written"," When the table is small and seldom written"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Why should you bundle database updates in your dialog programs? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" To process the SAP LUW within the database LUW to ensure data consistency"," To allow you to use SAP locks to ensure data consistency"," To avoid database locks set by an SQL statement that persists until the end of the program"," To be able to rollback database changes performed in the same dialog step"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following requirements can you implement a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A method to set an instance attribute with one importing parameter and no other parameters"," A handler method for an event that has a returning parameter"," A factory method that returns an object reference"," A private static helper method that returns a single value as the result of an algorithm"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data element property do you set so that the system logs changes to the content of fields with this data element? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" PARAMETER ID"," Documentation"," Input history"," Change document"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which of the following you must assign newly created SAP repository objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Transport request"," Transport task"," Function group"," Package"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Can identify where program behavior may change"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is an implicit enhancement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Private method"," Protected method"," Pre-method"," Overwrite method"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: When is a foreign key check performed on an input/output field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a value help is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a search is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a check table is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a append search is defined"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You always want to check the user authorization for data entered in an input field of a selection screen.Where do you do this? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" In the event block AT SELECTION-SCREEN on VALUE-REQUEST"," In the event block AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," In the event block INITIALIZATION"," In the event block AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which SELECT statement will always bypass the SAP table buffers? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � ENDSELECT."," SELECT � FOR UPDATE �"," SELECT � INTO TABLE �"," SELECT � SINGLE �"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What process is used to establish the automatic transport of data between the view controller's context-attributes and the UI element in its layout? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data migration"," Context mapping"," View assembly"," Data binding"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."," Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions are integrated in the ABAP workbench tools? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" ABAP editor (SE38)"," Overview of job selection (SM37)"," Process overview (SM50)"," Class builder (SE24)"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which parameter types can be used in the signature of a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" EXPORTING"," RETURNING"," CHANGING"," IMPORTING"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," CALL TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," SUBMIT"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following actions can be performed in the Process After Input (PAI) processing block? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Set the GUI status of the screen."," Check the function code."," Modify screen attributes dynamically."," Set the title bar."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You need to specify a key in the table declaration"," You can resort the table with SORT"," You can read the records by index or key"," You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: dbtab is a transparent table. What is declared by the following statement? DATA myvar TYPE dbtab. Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" An elementary field"," A reference to an internal table"," An internal table"," A structure variable"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The superclass method is an instance method"," The super class method is abstract"," The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to translate dynamic text in a web dynpro. From which abstract class should you inherit? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CL_WD_CONTEXT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_COMPONENT_ASSISTANCE"," CL_WD_COMPONENT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_CONFIGURATION_MODEL"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: A work process� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Uses a common memory area called shared memory."," Stays linked toa screen through the dispatcher."," Becomes active while waiting for a user."," Becomes inactive while waiting for a user."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you do with the code inspector? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Choose from only the performance, security and user interface check categories"," Create only local inspections, objects sets and check variants"," Create an object set to represent the programs and objects to be inspected"," Create your own inspections, object sets and check variants"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you define data types that can be accessed directly by all ABAp repository objects in an SAP system? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" In a global class"," In a function module"," In a method"," In the ABAP dictionary"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When starting the Debugger, what circumstance causes the runtime error�DEBUGGING_NOT_POSSIBLE? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When more than five sessions are already associated with this login user"," When more than six sessions are already associated with this login user"," Starting a non-exclusive mode in a productive system"," When the number of debugging sessions on the server exceeds the value defined by the profile parameter rdisp/wpdbug_max_no"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define an interface for the BAdI."," Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Call the BAdI"," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you save the program"," When you activate the program"," When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you perform a syntax check on the program"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to develop a validation routine for a selection screen field. If a wrong value is entered into the field an error message should be displayed and the focus should move to the field. Which event do you use to achieve this? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" START-OF-SELECTION"," END-OF-SELECTION"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," INITIALIZATION"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the Refactoring Assistant allow you to do? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Move components between superclasses and subclasses"," Move between classes and interfaces"," Rename all occurrences of a method"," Rename all subclasses of a method"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing an ABAP declaration using the data element S_CARR_ID. Which of the following statements correctly define a data object? There are 2 correct answers to this question. Note: Answers of this question are not verified by our experts, please study yourself and select the appropriate answers. ",Response: [" CONSTANTS gc_qf TYPE s_carr_id VALUE �QF�"," DATA gv_id TYPE s_carr_id"," DATA gv_id LIKE s_carr_id"," DATA gv_id TYPE s_carr_id DEFAULT �QF�"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: At most, how many menu items (including functions, separators and sub- menus) can a menu have on the screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 15"," 10"," 20"," None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following controller types can exist only once in a Web Dynpro component? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Component controller"," Window controller"," View controller"," Configuration controller"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Implicit enhancement can be used to enhance SAP objects developed prior to SAP NetWeaver 7.0."," An implicit enhancement point can be used to insert code in an SAP pro- gram and is always available to the customer."," Implicit enhancement options allow you to enhance interface parameters for function modules and methods without modifying the repository object."," None of the above."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Can identify where program behavior may change"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Function groups"," Executables"," Class pools"," Module pools"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following can you do with the SAP code inspector? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Monitor background tasks"," Perform static code checks"," Monitor runtime behavior"," Analyze runtime data."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What process is used to establish the automatic transport of data between the view controller's context-attributes and the UI element in its layout? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Context mapping"," View assembly"," Data binding"," Data migration"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A group of classes that describe the BDC�Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of hierarchal classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole but do not inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that apply Grid as a whole and inherit from a multiple class"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following functions does the ABAP Dispatcher perform? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" It directs HTTP requests from an SAP system to a web server."," It communicates with other instances in the system."," It distributes user requests among available work processes."," It enables communication between SAP systems and external application systems."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following enhancement options does not require any preparation from SAP? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Implicit enhancement point"," New BAdIs"," Explicit enhancement sections"," Explicit enhancement point"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP statements throws an error at the syntax check? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA variable"," DATA variable(5) TYPE t."," DATA variable(5) TYPE p."," DATA variable(5) TYPE n."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions can you use to define transparent tables? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SM37"," SE11"," SE16N"," SE38"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: The statements CALL BADI and GET BADI are used for which type of BAdIs? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Classical�DDic"," None of the above"," New BAdI"," Classical BAdI"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which rules do you have to consider when working with pooled tables? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" An append structure can be created"," Only key fields should be used in WHERE condition"," Only key fields should be used in ORDER BY clauses"," All fields can be used in indexes"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which method of passing parameters is preferred for its performance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Pass by subclass"," Pass by reference"," Pass by class"," Pass by value"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have written a program to output data using the ALV grid control. Which sequence of steps should be executed at runtime? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1. Create a grid object 2. Create a container object 3. Pass data to the grid object"," 1. Create a container object 2. Create a grid object 3. Pass data to the grid object"," 1. Pass data to the grid object 2. Create a container object 3. Create a grid object"," 1. Create a grid object 2. Pass data to the grid object 3. Create a container object"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In which database table type is there a one-to-one relationship between the Dictionary table definition and the relevant physical table in the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Cluster table"," Pooled table"," Internal table"," Transparent table"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Each ABAP program starts with an introductory statement. Which statements are correct? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The introductory statement can be modified."," The introductory statement must be the first statement in the program."," The introductory statement must never be modified."," The introductory statement must be the first line in the program."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You write the following ABAp statement: SELECT SINGLE carrid connid cityfrom cityto From spfli INTO gs_spfli WHERE carrid = pa_car AND connid = pa_con  How are the fields in the field list of the SELECT statement copied to the target structure gs_spfli? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" They are copied from right to left"," They are copied to fields with the same name"," They are copied from left to right"," They are copied to fields with the same type"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement ends a screen sequence and starts from initial screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE SCREEN"," LEAVE TO SCREEN"," SET SCREEN 0"," CALL SCREEN"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default selection screen number for the ABAP program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1000"," 1100"," 100"," None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following rules must you follow when creating subscreens? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subscreens CANNOT have a field of type OK."," Subscreens can call other subscreens."," Subscreens CANNOT have an AT EXIT-COMMAND module."," Subscreens can have a dialog module containing SET PF-STATUS."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the allowed length of the ABAP Dictionary data type DF16_DEC? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The allowed length is between 0 and 15 digits."," The allowed length is between 1 and 15 digits."," The allowed length is 16 digits."," The allowed length is between 0 and 16 digits."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You define a database view A and maintenance view B in the ABAP dictionary. What restrictions apply to these views? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Only A can be used in the FROM clause of a SELECT statement"," The tables joined in B must have foreign key relationships"," Only B can have either a left outer join or an inner join"," The tables joined in A must have foreign key relationships"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which view types can you use to join two tables with an outer join? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Projection view"," Maintenance view"," Help view"," Database view"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements regarding the event AT SELECTIONSCREEN ON HELP-REQUEST FOR <FIELD> is correct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above."," This event will display self-defined (F1) help for the output field programmed in the event block and will override any help possibly defined in the�ABAP�Dictionary for the field."," This event will display (F1) help for the input field on the selection screen."," This event will display self-defined (F1) help for the input field programmed in the event block and will override any help possibly defined in the ABAP Dictionary for the field."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to move a transport request from the development system to the subsequent system. Which of the following are prerequisites for this? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" All objects included in the transport request must be activated."," All tasks of the transport request must be assigned to the same user."," The extended program check must show no warnings."," The transport request must be released"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is data binding? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Connecting one Web Dynpro component to another Web Dynpro component"," Connecting the values of user interface elements to the context attributes of the corresponding controller"," Connecting an outbound plug on one view to the inbound plug of another view"," Connecting a context node in one controller to a context node in another controller"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP statements throws an error at the syntax check? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA variable(5) TYPE p."," DATA variable(5) TYPE n."," DATA variable"," DATA variable(5) TYPE t."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CUKY"," CURR"," DEC"," UNIT"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the predefined reference variable used in ABAP OO to address the object itself? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" THIS"," ME"," SUPER"," SELF"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: A view can only be displayed in which circumstances? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It can always be displayed."," It cannot always be displayed."," It has been embedded in a window."," It contains an inbound and outbound plug."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: DOG is a subclass of ANIMAL. You have created a variable of type ANIMAL that references an instance of the DOG class. Which of the following statements can you use to copy this reference to a new variable of type DOG? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" MOVE��?TO��"," MOVE-CORRESPONDING�� TO��"," WRITE��TO��"," MOVE�. TO�.."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you have to take into account before you decide to buffer a table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The database server must allow table buffering"," The data read from the buffer may NOT be current"," The data must always be read from the buffer"," The entire table content must be loaded into the table buffer"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the CALL CUSTOMER-FUNCTION 'nnn' statement, nnn is a three-digit number�used in SAP programs for which of the following types of enhancement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Business add-ins"," User exits"," New BAdIs"," Customer exits"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following components belong to the SAP application layer? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" ABAP dispatcher"," Database server"," SAP GUI"," Database interface"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."," All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When must a foreign key have domain equality? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" For a check field"," For a text table"," Always"," Never"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: To reserve an area on the screen for an ALV Grid Control, you must do the following: Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Use the Screen Painter"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."," Each statement must end with a period."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you add fields to an SAP-delivered transparent table without modification? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add the new fields to the table definition."," Use the database utility to enhance the definition on the database directly."," Create an append structure containing the new fields."," Define a structure containing the new fields and include it in the table definition."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you save the program"," When you perform a syntax check on the program"," When you activate the program"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are characteristics of a hashed internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" It must have a unique key."," It can be accessed using the key."," It can be accessed using the index."," It can have a non-unique key."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."," The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of transport task is used when you modify SAP standard objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Transport of copies"," Repair"," Development/Correction"," Workbench"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You implemented a subclass that inherits the instance constructor from it superclass�What can you do with the inherited constructor? There are 2 correct answers to this question. Note: Answers of this question are not verified by our experts, please study yourself and select the appropriate answers. ",Response: [" Redefine the implementation"," Create several implementations"," Change the signature"," Change the name"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When would you call the RFC function module synchronously? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" During interactive communication"," During queue processing"," During two-way communication"," During unidirectional communication"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to create a transparent table in the ABAP dictionary. When the table is physically created in the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you activate the table"," When you run the database utility transaction (SE14)"," When you save the table"," When you insert the table name and select create"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" PARAMETERS"," SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"," SELECT-OPTIONS"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You define a formal parameter to a subroutine that accepts only internal table of type standard and type sorted as actual parameters. Which of the following generic ABAP data types must you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Standard table"," Index table"," Sorted table"," Hashed table"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In addition to the primary key of an internal table, how many secondary indexes can you define for an internal table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 10","15"," 1"," 0"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the difference between SAP Basis and SAP NetWeaver? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" All versions of SAP�NetWeaver�require the use of�UTF-8."," There is no difference; the name change was driven by marketing alone."," All versions of SAP NetWeaver include the ability to handle HTTP requests."," All versions of SAP NetWeaver require the use of Unicode."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" By running Transaction UCCHECK"," Cannot be enforced"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"," You can read the records by index or key"," You can resort the table with SORT"," You need to specify a key in the table declaration"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which property of the InputField UI element must be bound to a context attribute? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" visible"," value"," state"," enable"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have implemented a class CL_CUSTOMER in which you defined a private attribute. From where can you access this attribute directly? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" From all methods of all subclasses of CL_CUSTOMER"," From any program using the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of a class to which CL_CUSTOMER grants friendship"," From all methods of the class CL_CUSTOMER"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following structures is created when you use a table type to define one of its components? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Append structure"," Nested structure"," Deep structure"," Flat structure"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When must a foreign key have domain equality? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Always"," Never"," For a text table"," For a check field"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a program that uses ABAP class. Which components of the class can you create directly from the program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Only protected components"," All components"," Only private components"," Only public components"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following standard types is numeric? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" F"," I"," Decfloat32"," P"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: SAP enhancements for customer exits are managed by which transaction? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Neither transaction listed here"," Transaction CMOD"," Transaction SMOD"," Application�CMOD"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to display a dialog box in your ABAP program. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" WINDOW 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," CALL SCREEN 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," CALL SCREEN 200."," SET SCREEN 200."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to read data from two database tables A and B using a database join. Database table B contains details for data records stored in database table A. Your result should contain all combinations of matching rows from A and B plus all rows from A that do not have matching rows in B. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � FROM a JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM b RIGHT OUTER JOIN a �"," SELECT � FROM a INNER JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM a LEFT OUTER JOIN b �"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To reserve an area on the screen for an ALV Grid Control, you must do the following: Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Use the Screen Painter"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."," Each statement must end with a period."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Execute command /h"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The superclass method is an instance method"," The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"," The super class method is abstract"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Each button on a Dynpro (screen) requires the assignment of a function�code. This function code� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Prevents the function code from be assigned to a category item."," Is used to define global variables that receive a value when the button is clicked."," Can be used to identify when the button is clicked by looking for the function code in the screen�s OK_CODE field."," Prevents the function code from be assigned to a menu item."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Global data types defined in SAP systems are� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Date types does not defined Dictionary types."," ABAP Dictionary types."," Data defined in the program that is visible to all the routines/statements within the ABAP program."," Date types defined in the program using ABAP Dictionary types."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Private event and private handler"," Public event and protected handler"," Private event and public handler"," Protected event and public handler"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you use to achieve polymorphism? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Reports"," Inheritance"," Events"," Subroutines"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which objects can share data through context mapping? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" View controller and another view controller"," Global classes and component controllers"," Custom controllers and transparent tables"," Component controllers and view controllers"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You create a function group ZATP. What is the name of the corresponding main program? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SAPFZATP"," ZATP"," SAPMZATP"," SAPLZATP"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you create lock objects and lock modules for use in ABAP programs that access the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules and the lock objects","Use the ABAP Dictionary to create the lock objects. The lock modules are created automatically"," Use the Function Builder to create the lock modules. The lock objects are created in the program logic"," Use the ABAP dictionary to create the lock objects. Use the function builder to create the lock modules"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search helps"," Append searches","Maintenance screens","Events"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the CALL CUSTOMER-FUNCTION 'nnn' statement, nnn is a three-digit number�used in SAP programs for which of the following types of enhancement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" New BAdIs"," User exits"," Customer exits"," Business add-ins"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When would you call the RFC function module synchronously? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: ["During queue processing","During two-way communication"," During interactive communication"," During unidirectional communication"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What scheduling technique is used by the ABAP debugger dispatcher for processing user requests? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Multiple Queue"," Shortest First","First in , First out"," Round Robin"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which database objects can you create in the ABAP Dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Logical databases","Projection views","Indexes"," Foreign key relationships"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following characters is the first of a menu exit function code? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" *"," -","+"," &"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: A view can only be displayed in which circumstances? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It can always be displayed."," It has been embedded in a window."," It contains an inbound and outbound plug."," It cannot always be displayed."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The transport layer is a mandatory input field for the package."," Packages use interfaces and visibility to make their elements visible to other packages."," A package can be nested."," All customer repository objects have to be assigned to a package."],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP standard types are incomplete? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" X"," F"," N"," STRING"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of transport task is used when you modify SAP standard objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Development/Correction"," Workbench"," Transport of copies"," Repair"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You can use the logical expression IS SUPPLIED for any formal parameter passed to which modularization unit? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: ["Instance method","Static method"," Subroutine (FORM routine)","Function module"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type P data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1"," 8"," 64"," 42370"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which objects are automatically created when you create a new function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A function pool and two subroutine pools"," A function pool and two function modules"," A function pool and two module pools"," A function pool and two include programs"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What data type you can create in the ABAP Dictionary? Please choose the correct answer ",Response: [" Type group"," Secondary index"," Lock object"," Structure"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" UNIT"," CURR"," CUKY"," DEC"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(2) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Table fields can be assigned to an ABAP Dictionary data type directly."," Table fields can be assigned to a data element."," A reference table and field are required for fields with the data types QUAN and CURR."," Search helps can be defined for a table field that is assigned to a predefined data type."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is variable-length structure called? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Nested link structure"," Nested structure"," Flat structure"," Link structure"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does the lifetime of a Web Dynpro component begin and end? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It begins each time it is called, and it ends when the component completes."," It begins when instantiated and it ends when the program ends or the object is freed."," It begins the first time it is called at runtime, and it ends with the Web Dynpro application that called and instantiated the component ends."," It ends each time it is called, and it ends when the component completes."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which context object is the attribute LEAD_SELECTION_INDEX related? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Node"," Supply function"," Attribute"," Element"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," Cannot be enforced"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which action on the underlying dictionary objects triggers a database table conversion? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Inserting a field of type reference"," Reducing the size of the field."," Inserting an APPEND structure"," Changing the order of non-key fields"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have implemented a class CL_CUSTOMER in which you defined a private attribute. From where can you access this attribute directly? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" From all methods of the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From any program using the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of all subclasses of CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of a class to which CL_CUSTOMER grants friendship"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the difference between a Unicode and non-Unicode program? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" Byte-type data objects cannot be assigned to character-type data objects."," Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to flat data objects."," Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to character data objects."," Byte-type data objects cannot be compared to character-type data objects."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled when using a GROUP BY clause in a SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The SELECT statement must also have a WHERE clause."," The fields after GROUP BY must have a character type."," The table in the FROM clause must be a transparent table."," All fields in the SELECT clause that are not part of an aggregate function must be listed after GROUP BY."],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you change in the ABAP Debugger? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Value of a constant","Content of an internal table"," Value of a reference variable"," Definition of a structure"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which hook method exists for all controller types? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" wddoonopen( )"," wddoinit( )"," wddobeforenavigation( )"," wddoonclose( )"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Public event and protected handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Private event and private handler"," Private event and public handler"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A static attribute is the same across all instances of the class. There is only one static attribute across all instances of the class."," Static attributes cannot be changed by an object."," Static attributes are declared with the CLASS-DATA statement."," Static attributes can be declared only in the private visibility section of the class."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUBMIT"," CALL TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The superclass method is an instance method"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"," The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"," The super class method is abstract"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you improve the performance when accessing a large data volume database table? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define appropriate indexes for the database table."," Switch the database table to fully buffered."," Change the table type in the dictionary"," Apply the appropriate data class and size category."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the predefined reference variable used in ABAP OO to address the object itself? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELF"," ME"," THIS"," SUPER"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."," All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "",Response: [" You can use a database view for the search help selection method."," You can use transparent tables for the search help selection method."," Help views can also be used for the selection method for search help."," You can use a maintenance view for the search help selection method."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is an implicit enhancement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: ["Private method","Protected method"," Pre-method"," Overwrite method"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."," Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Why should you bundle database updates in your dialog programs? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" To be able to rollback database changes performed in the same dialog step"," To avoid database locks set by an SQL statement that persists until the end of the program"," To allow you to use SAP locks to ensure data consistency"," To process the SAP LUW within the database LUW to ensure data consistency"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: To reserve an area on the screen for an ALV Grid Control, you must do the following: Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"," Use the Screen Painter"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the SAP recommended naming convention for append structures of standard SAPtables? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The name of the append structure must start with ZA."," The components of an append structure should start with ZZ or YY."," The components of an append structure should start with Z or Y."," The name of the append structure must start with ZZ or YY."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In addition to the primary key of an internal table, how many secondary indexes can you define for an internal table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 0"," 1","15"," 10"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."," The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: ["Function groups","Module pools"," Class pools","Executables"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How many kinds of internal tables are supported in the ABAP language? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 2"," 5","3"," 1"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to define two database tables with different structures. Both tables should contain the fields CHANGE_DATE and CHANGE_TIME. How do you implement this in order to minimize the maintenance effort? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define the two fields in one database table and copy them to the other database table."," Define the two fields in each database table separately."," Define a structure with these two fields and include this structure in both database tables."," Define an append structure with these two fields and assign this append structure to both database tables."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," CALL TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Execute command /h"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."," Call the BAdI"," Define an interface for the BAdI."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can only specify default values for the LOW and HIGH fields of the SELECT-OPTIONS input field.","The SELECT-OPTIONS statement creates an internal table with a header line. The internal table is also known as the selection table.","You can use the addition NO-DISPLAY to hide the input field on the selection screen.","The structure of the selection table created with SELECT-OPTIONS has four components: SIGN, OPTION, LOW, and HIGH."],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP statements throws an error at the syntax check? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA variable(5) TYPE t."," DATA variable(5) TYPE p."," DATA variable"," DATA variable(5) TYPE n."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following controller types can exist only once in a Web Dynpro component? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: ["Configuration controller"," Window controller"," View controller","Component controller"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which view types can you use to join two tables with an outer join? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Help view"," Maintenance view"," Database view"," Projection view"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You run an executable program which contains the following code: DATA: gv_var1 TYPE n LENGTH 3, Gv_var2 TYPE n LENGTH 3 VALUE �456�. START-OF-SELECTION CLEAR gv_var2 Gv_var2 = gv_var1. Gv_var1 = �123�.  At what point does the system reserve memory for the data object gv_var1?Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" As soon as the program is loaded into thie internal session"," When the value �123� is assigned to the data object"," At the beginning of the START-OF-SELECTION event block"," When the assignment to gv_var2 is executed"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to translate dynamic text in a web dynpro. From which abstract class should you inherit? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CL_WD_COMPONENT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_COMPONENT_ASSISTANCE"," CL_WD_CONFIGURATION_MODEL"," CL_WD_CONTEXT_SERVICES"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following values are replaceable in debugger mode? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Variables"," Field names"," Table names"," Constants"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you set the GUI status and the GUI title for a classical screen (dynpro)? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" In a module called from PAI of the screen"," In a module called from PBO of the screen"," In the attributes of the screen"," In the properties of the related header UI element"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: To reserve an area on the screen for an ALV Grid Control, you must do the following: Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the Screen Painter"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_SALV_TABLE"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_ALV_GRID"," Create an object (instantiate the object) of the class CL_GUI_CUSTOM_CONTAINER"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(1) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."," You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."," The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," Field labels are defined for the domain."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: ["All standard SQL commands can be used","It can be used with any DBMS","Syntax is checked at design time","The application server buffer is NOT used"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the root class in the RTTS inheritance tree? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["CL_ABAP_TYPEDESCR"," CL_ABAP_COMPLEXDESCR"," CL_ABAP_DATADESCR"," CL_ABAP_ELEMDESCR"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Each component has an interface; of what does this interface consist? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Data Container"," Interface context"," Interface controller"," Interface view"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does the lifetime of a component controller begin and end? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It lasts from creating data within the controller to cover the whole period during which the component is in use."," It begins with the Web Dynpro component and ends with the Web Dynpro application that called it."," It begins the first time the Web Dynpro application is called at runtime and ends when the Web Dynpro application that called and instantiated the component ends."," It ends the first time the Web�Dynpro�application is called at runtime and ends when the Web�Dynpro�application that called and�instantiated�the component ends."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: At most, how many menu items (including functions, separators and sub- menus) can a menu have on the screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["15","20","10","None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: When starting the Debugger, what circumstance causes the runtime error�DEBUGGING_NOT_POSSIBLE? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Starting a non-exclusive mode in a productive system"," When the number of debugging sessions on the server exceeds the value defined by the profile parameter rdisp/wpdbug_max_no"," When more than six sessions are already associated with this login user"," When more than five sessions are already associated with this login user"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you find customer exists in an ABAP program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search for �CALL CUSTOMER� in the program"," Search for �CL_EXTHANDLER� in the program."," Search for customer exists in the program documentation"," Search for customer exists in the Repository Information System"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You need to specify a key in the table declaration"," You can resort the table with SORT"," You can read the records by index or key"," You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following rules must you follow when creating subscreens? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subscreens can have a dialog module containing SET PF-STATUS."," Subscreens CANNOT have a field of type OK."," Subscreens can call other subscreens."," Subscreens CANNOT have an AT EXIT-COMMAND module."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you define local classes in ABAP, which syntactical sequence must you follow? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" PRIVATE SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PUBLIC SECTION"," The order is handled automatically."," PUBLIC SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PRIVATE SECTION"," The order doesn�t matter."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is data binding? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Connecting one Web Dynpro component to another Web Dynpro component"," Connecting an outbound plug on one view to the inbound plug of another view"," Connecting a context node in one controller to a context node in another controller"," Connecting the values of user interface elements to the context attributes of the corresponding controller"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do global types and local types have in common? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Documentation"," Field labels"," Search help"," Technical information"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following ABAP statements throws an error at the syntax check? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA variable(5) TYPE p."," DATA variable"," DATA variable(5) TYPE t."," DATA variable(5) TYPE n."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT"," CALL TRANSACTION"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which hook method exists for all controller types? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" wddoonclose( )"," wddobeforenavigation( )"," wddoinit( )"," wddoonopen( )"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have implemented a class CL_CUSTOMER in which you defined a private attribute. From where can you access this attribute directly? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" From all methods of the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of a class to which CL_CUSTOMER grants friendship"," From any program using the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of all subclasses of CL_CUSTOMER"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following function types in a GUI status are reserved for internal use? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" S- SYSTEM"," E-EXIT"," H-HELP REQUEST"," T-TRANSACTION"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which context object is the attribute LEAD_SELECTION_INDEX related? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Element"," Node"," Supply function"," Attribute"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DEC"," CURR"," UNIT"," CUKY"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" SELECT-OPTIONS"," PARAMETERS"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"," SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which method of passing parameters is preferred for its performance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Pass by subclass"," Pass by reference"," Pass by class"," Pass by value"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What process is used to establish the automatic transport of data between the view controller's context-attributes and the UI element in its layout? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data migration"," Data binding"," Context mapping"," View assembly"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you maintain documentation for input fields on your screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT (PBO)."," Add documentation to the SCREEN table at PROCESS AFTER INPUT (PAI)."," Add documentation to the underlying data element."," Define text tables for the underlying structure."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of creating a database view to implement a join, instead of formulating the join directly in an Open SQL SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" A database view can be buffered"," A database view can be reused in other programs"," An outer join can only be implemented in a database view"," A secondary index can be created for a database view"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" By running Transaction UCCHECK"," Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Cannot be enforced"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Private event and public handler"," Private event and private handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Public event and protected handler"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LxxxxF01"," LxxxxO01"," LxxxxTOP"," LxxxxUXX"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which parameter types can be used in the signature of a functional method? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" IMPORTING"," RETURNING"," CHANGING"," EXPORTING"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: The data buffered on each application server� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Depends on the users."," Is always the same."," Is does not the same."," Is never the same."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the prerequisites when creating an append structure for a standard SAP table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The fields in the append structure should star with YY or ZZ"," The table cannot have any fields of type FLTP"," The table must be copied before the append structure can be created"," The enhancement category of the table is NOT set to �Not enhacable�"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Cannot be enforced"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Global data types defined in SAP systems are� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Date types defined in the program using ABAP Dictionary types."," ABAP Dictionary types."," Date types does not defined Dictionary types."," Data defined in the program that is visible to all the routines/statements within the ABAP program."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."," All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following rules must you follow when creating subscreens? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subscreens can have a dialog module containing SET PF-STATUS."," Subscreens can call other subscreens."," Subscreens CANNOT have an AT EXIT-COMMAND module."," Subscreens CANNOT have a field of type OK."],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which SELECT statement will always bypass the SAP table buffers? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � INTO TABLE �"," SELECT � FOR UPDATE �"," SELECT � ENDSELECT."," SELECT � SINGLE �"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 100"," 1"," 1�65535"," 10"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the Web Dynpro programming model is based on? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Internet Transaction Server (ITS)"," Model View Controller (MVC)"," Business Server Pages (BSPs)"," Classic Dynpro programming"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following must you do to be able to use a Business Add-in(BADI)? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Activate the enhancement project"," Modify the adapter class"," Write code for methods"," Create the BADI implementation"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions can you use to define transparent tables? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SM37"," SE38"," SE16N"," SE11"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(1) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."," The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," Field labels are defined for the domain."," Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you add programming logic to your ABAP program that checks authorizations,which of the following do you have to create? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An authorization object"," An authorization Access"," An authorization role"," An authorization profile"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: There are ____ versions of the ABAP Editor. Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 4"," 1","3"," 2"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following standard types is numeric? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Decfloat32"," P"," I"," F"],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Execute command /h"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."," The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A group of hierarchal classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole but do not inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that describe the BDC�Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that apply Grid as a whole and inherit from a multiple class"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To activate logging for transparent tables"," To create lock objects"," To create development classes"," To maintain program translations"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which hook method exists for all controller types? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" wddobeforenavigation( )"," wddoonclose( )"," wddoinit( )"," wddoonopen( )"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An enhancement spot can contain one or more simple or composite enhancements."," An enhancement spot can contain an explicit enhancement point and an enhancement section."," An enhancement spot can contain an explicit enhancement point, explicit enhancement section, and new BAdI."," An enhancement spot can contain either an explicit enhancement point and enhancement section or a new BAdI only, but all three cannot be in the same enhancement spot."],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to define data structures to hold two fields with data elements s_carr_id and s_carrname. Which of the following�declarations can be used to define this data structure? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" DATA BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gty_flight"," DATA: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"," TYPES: BEGIN OF gs_flight,"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."," Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You need to perform a downcast. What should you do? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Use the operator �=�."," Perform the downcast only if an upcast has already been done for the object reference."," Catch the exception CX_SY_MOVE_CAST_ERROR."," Assign a subclass reference to a superclass reference."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LxxxxUXX"," LxxxxO01"," LxxxxF01"," LxxxxTOP"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to select data from two tables and store the result in as structure. Table PARTNER contains the fields PART_ID and KIND. Table CONTRACT contains the fields CONT_ID, CONT_TYPE and DIVISION. The structure is defined as follows DATA: BEGIN OF wa_result, Part_id type partner-part_id,� cont_id type contract-cont_id, Cont_type� TYPE contract-cont_type, END of wa_result, Lt_result type table of wa_result. How can you replace the following SELECT statement with an outer join? SELECT part_id from partner INTO wa_result WHERE kind = �Residential�.� SELECT cont_id from CONTRACT into wa_result-cont_id WHERE part EQ ��� wa_partner-part_id And DIVISION eq �Water�.� Append wa_result to lt_result.�� ENDSELECT. �If sy-subrc<>0. CLEAR wa_result-cont_id �APPEND wa_result TO lt_result. ENDIF. ��ENDSELECT.Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT part_idcont_id from partner LEFT JOIN contract on partner-part_id = contract-part_id AND contract-division EQ �Water� INTO TABLE lt_result WHERE kind EQ �Residential�."," SELECT part_idcont_id from partner AS A LEFT JOIN contract AS b ON a~part_id = b~part_id INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF TABLE lt_result WHERE kind = �Residential� and AND division EQ �Water�."," SELECT part_idcont_id from partner LEFT JOIN contract on partner-part_id = contract-part_id AND partner-kind EQ �Residential� INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF TABLE lt_result WHERE division eq �Water�."," SELECT part_idcont_id from partner AS A LEFT JOIN contract AS b ON a~part_id = b~part_id AND b~division EQ �Water� INTO TABLElt_result WHERE kind = �Residential�"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: If you are using external debugging (debugging of HTTP and RFC requests,�which arrive in your ABAP system), what will the Debugger do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Never stop; external breakpoints operate on users other than your own."," May or may not stop, depending on external factors."," Always stop when the external breakpoint is reached."," Do not stop when the external breakpoint is reached."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is correct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT event block."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS AFTER INPUT event block."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT and PROCESS AFTER INPUT event blocks."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the CALL CUSTOMER-FUNCTION 'nnn' statement, nnn is a three-digit number�used in SAP programs for which of the following types of enhancement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Customer exits"," Business add-ins"," User exits"," New BAdIs"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Implicit enhancement options allow you to enhance interface parameters for function modules and methods without modifying the repository object."," Implicit enhancement can be used to enhance SAP objects developed prior to SAP NetWeaver 7.0."," None of the above."," An implicit enhancement point can be used to insert code in an SAP pro- gram and is always available to the customer."],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You can resort the table with SORT"," You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"," You can read the records by index or key"," You need to specify a key in the table declaration"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view cannot be used in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Database view"," Maintenance view"," Candidates key view"," Help view"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which you should specify in a non-Unicode system when opening a file in TEXT MODE? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The code page"," The byte order"," The ENCODING addition"," The storage order"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DEC"," UNIT"," CURR"," CUKY"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does the lifetime of a component controller begin and end? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It begins with the Web Dynpro component and ends with the Web Dynpro application that called it."," It begins the first time the Web Dynpro application is called at runtime and ends when the Web Dynpro application that called and instantiated the component ends."," It lasts from creating data within the controller to cover the whole period during which the component is in use."," It ends the first time the Web�Dynpro�application is called at runtime and ends when the Web�Dynpro�application that called and�instantiated�the component ends."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Using the screen system table, what can you modify through a LOOP AT SCREEN � ENDLOOP construct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Function code of buttons"," Attributes of screen elements"," Values of screen elements"," Screen status"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Cannot be enforced"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following customer modifications options are available in the table maintenance generator? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Append searches"," Search helps"," Maintenance screens"," Events"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."," Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements?(1) There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."," You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."," Field labels are defined for the domain."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following capabilities is provided by the Application Layer platform of SAP Netweaver? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Business process management"," Multi-channel access"," Master data management"," Database and operating system abstraction"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: The data buffered on each application server� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Is never the same."," Is always the same."," Is does not the same."," Depends on the users."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement will interrupt the processing of the current screen and branch to new screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CALL SCREEN <NNNN>"," LEAVE TO SCREEN <NNNN>"," SET SCREEN <NNNN>"," None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What type of ABAP Dictionary view is implemented as an INNER JOIN? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Database view"," Help view"," Maintenance view"," Projection view"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following tasks does the BADI implementing class perform? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Inserting"," Deleting"," Sequencing"," Filtering"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"," PARAMETERS"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"," SELECT-OPTIONS"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the prerequisites when creating an append structure for a standard SAP table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The table must be copied before the append structure can be created"," The enhancement category of the table is NOT set to �Not enhacable�"," The fields in the append structure should star with YY or ZZ"," The table cannot have any fields of type FLTP"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you embed a subscreen in a main screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use CALL SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen"," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The SELECT-OPTIONS statement creates an internal table with a header line. The internal table is also known as the selection table."," You can use the addition NO-DISPLAY to hide the input field on the selection screen."," The structure of the selection table created with SELECT-OPTIONS has four components: SIGN, OPTION, LOW, and HIGH."," You can only specify default values for the LOW and HIGH fields of the SELECT-OPTIONS input field."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Each statement must end with a period."," ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your selection screen can be modified at which event? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN ON <field_name>"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Selection method"," Fixed values"," Attachment to a field"," Import / export parameters"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"," Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Can identify where program behavior may change"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of transport task is used when you modify SAP standard objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Transport of copies"," Development/Correction"," Workbench"," Repair"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following types of SQL statements always bypass the SAP table buffers? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" SELECT � INNER JOIN�"," SELECT SINGLE"," SELECT SUM (sales)"," SELECT � UP TO 1 ROW"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: A view can only be displayed in which circumstances? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It contains an inbound and outbound plug."," It can always be displayed."," It has been embedded in a window."," It cannot always be displayed."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you need to consider when creating a secondary index on a table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The table will be updated more quickly if you create more indexes"," The index must always be unique"," The index can be created for specific database systems only"," The most frequently selected fields should be at the first positions in the index"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" They facilitate multilingual functionality"," The same text symbol can be used by other programs"," They are easier to maintain than literals"," Then can store up to 256 characters"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," Cannot be enforced"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions can you use to define transparent tables? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SM37"," SE11"," SE16N"," SE38"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are features of the Context in Web Dynpro? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Every Web Dynpro controller has one Context"," Data is transferred from one Context to another by firing plugs"," Every Web Dynpro controller has multiple Contexts"," Data is shared between controllers through Context mapping"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You need to perform a downcast. What should you do? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Use the operator �=�."," Assign a subclass reference to a superclass reference."," Catch the exception CX_SY_MOVE_CAST_ERROR."," Perform the downcast only if an upcast has already been done for the object reference."],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Execute command /h"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUBMIT� AND RETURN"," LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," CALL TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you declare an internal table using the transparent table A as its line type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DATA gt_itab TYPE a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE TABLE OF a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE LINE OF a."," DATA gt_itab TYPE REF TO a."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Can identify where program behavior may change"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To activate logging for transparent tables"," To create development classes"," To create lock objects"," To maintain program translations"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Global data types defined in SAP systems are� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Data defined in the program that is visible to all the routines/statements within the ABAP program."," ABAP Dictionary types."," Date types defined in the program using ABAP Dictionary types."," Date types does not defined Dictionary types."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."," Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Call the BAdI"," Define an interface for the BAdI."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of transport task is used when you modify SAP standard objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Workbench"," Transport of copies"," Repair"," Development/Correction"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does SAP recommend that you use a full buffering type for a database table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When the table is large and frequently written"," When the table is small and frequently written"," When the table is small and seldom written"," When the table is large and seldom written"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: After which statement will the runtime system initialize the ABAP memory Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUBMIT"," CALL TRANSACTION"," LEAVE TO TRANSACTION"," SUBMIT� AND RETURN"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Implicit enhancement options allow you to enhance interface parameters for function modules and methods without modifying the repository object."," An implicit enhancement point can be used to insert code in an SAP pro- gram and is always available to the customer."," Implicit enhancement can be used to enhance SAP objects developed prior to SAP NetWeaver 7.0."," None of the above."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: At most, how many menu items (including functions, separators and sub- menus) can a menu have on the screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["15"," 10"," 20"," None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Executables"," Function groups"," Class pools"," Module pools"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What happens when an authorization check fails? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The system field SY-SUBRC is set to a value other than zero."," The program is terminated."," A CX_AUTH_FAILED type exception is raised."," A type E message is displayed."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 1�65535"," 10"," 100"," 1"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components of the class can be accessed in the implementation of a static method in that class? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Instance attributes"," Constants"," Types"," All events"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you add a session breakpoint to your program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Execute command /h"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP debugger and press F8"," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor and select Save."," Set a breakpoint in the ABAP editor"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You use Unified Modelling language (UML) to design your classes. You want to describe the message exchange between objects. Which diagram can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Class diagram"," Component diagram"," Sequence diagram"," Object diagram"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements regarding search helps are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can use a maintenance view for the search help selection method."," Help views can also be used for the selection method for search help."," You can use a database view for the search help selection method."," You can use transparent tables for the search help selection method."],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"," Can identify where program behavior may change"," Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following variables is the self-reference variable in ABAP OO? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" THIS"," ME"," SUPER"," SENDER"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which view types can you use to join two tables with an outer join? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Maintenance view"," Projection view"," Database view"," Help view"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data element property do you set so that the system logs changes to the content of fields with this data element? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Documentation"," Input history"," PARAMETER ID"," Change document"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" A static attribute is the same across all instances of the class. There is only one static attribute across all instances of the class."," Static attributes cannot be changed by an object."," Static attributes are declared with the CLASS-DATA statement."," Static attributes can be declared only in the private visibility section of the class."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following enhancements calls a customer function module. There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Business Add-in (BADIs)"," Business Transaction event"," Customer exit"," User exit"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be part of the signature of an instance constructor? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Export parameters"," Exceptions"," Import parameters"," Changing parameters"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the purpose of implicit enhancement points? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" To create a secondary index for an SAP database table"," To add fields to an SAP database table"," To change code in a standard SAP program"," To add code to a standard SAP program"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following tasks does the BADI implementing class perform? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Sequencing"," Deleting"," Filtering"," Inserting"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following controller types can exist only once in a Web Dynpro component? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Window controller"," Component controller"," View controller"," Configuration controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view cannot be used in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Candidates key view"," Maintenance view"," Database view"," Help view"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are correct?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You can use the addition NO-DISPLAY to hide the input field on the selection screen."," The SELECT-OPTIONS statement creates an internal table with a header line. The internal table is also known as the selection table."," The structure of the selection table created with SELECT-OPTIONS has four components: SIGN, OPTION, LOW, and HIGH."," You can only specify default values for the LOW and HIGH fields of the SELECT-OPTIONS input field."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What process is used to establish the automatic transport of data between the view controller's context-attributes and the UI element in its layout? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" View assembly"," Data binding"," Data migration"," Context mapping"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"," Cannot be enforced"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view uses an inner join in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Database view"," Help view"," Maintenance view"," Candidate key view"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of creating a database view to implement a join, instead of formulating the join directly in an Open SQL SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" A database view can be reused in other programs"," An outer join can only be implemented in a database view"," A secondary index can be created for a database view"," A database view can be buffered"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["LxxxxTOP"," LxxxxUXX"," LxxxxO01"," LxxxxF01"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to use a BAdI to extend the functions of an SAP program. Which of the following tasks is necessary? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Call the BAdI"," Create an enhancement project using a customer exit."," Implement a class that implements the BAdI interface."," Define an interface for the BAdI."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you define data types that can be accessed directly by all ABAp repository objects in an SAP system? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" In a function module"," In a global class"," In the ABAP dictionary"," In a method"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following structures is created when you use a table type to define one of its components? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Nested structure"," Deep structure"," Append structure"," Flat structure"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the predefined reference variable used in ABAP OO to address the object itself? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SUPER"," THIS"," ME"," SELF"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to display a dialog box in your ABAP program. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CALL SCREEN 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," CALL SCREEN 200."," SET SCREEN 200."," WINDOW 200 STARTING AT 5 5."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following types of SQL statements always bypass the SAP table buffers? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" SELECT � INNER JOIN�"," SELECT � UP TO 1 ROW"," SELECT SINGLE"," SELECT SUM (sales)"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."," Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have defined a classical screen (dynpro) with mandatory input fields. You want to exit the screen using the Cancel button even if not all of the mandatory fields have been filled. What is necessary to achieve this? �Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use the LOOP AT SCREEN. ... ENDLOOP statement to set the 'required' property of the input fields to zero."," Set the function type assigned to the Cancel button to S and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."," Assign function type E to the Cancel button and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."," Set the function code assigned to the Cancel button to CANCEL and handle it in a module with the addition AT EXIT-COMMAND."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be exposed in the component interface of a Web dynpro component? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Custom methods of the component controller"," Context nodes of WINDOW controllers"," Public attributes of WINDOW controllers"," Standard hook methods of the component controller"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the prerequisites when creating an append structure for a standard SAP table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The enhancement category of the table is NOT set to �Not enhacable�"," The table must be copied before the append structure can be created"," The table cannot have any fields of type FLTP"," The fields in the append structure should star with YY or ZZ"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which selection screen elements allow user input in ABAP Reports? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" SELECTION-SCREEN COMMENT"," PARAMETERS"," SELECT-OPTIONS"," SELECTION-SCREEN BLOCK"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the purpose of the enqueuer work process? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["It processes user entries","It translates Open SQL statements","It manages logical locks in the lock table","It processes update requests"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What data type you can create in the ABAP Dictionary? Please choose the correct answer ",Response: [" Secondary index"," Type group"," Structure"," Lock object"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the ALV Object Model? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A group of hierarchal classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole but do not inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that apply Grid as a whole and inherit from a multiple class"," A group of classes that describe the BDC�Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"," A group of classes that describe the ALV Grid as a whole and inherit from a single class"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" They facilitate multilingual functionality"," The same text symbol can be used by other programs"," Then can store up to 256 characters"," They are easier to maintain than literals"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is correct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT and PROCESS AFTER INPUT event blocks."," None of the above."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS AFTER INPUT event block."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT event block."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The application server buffer is NOT used"," Syntax is checked at design time"," It can be used with any DBMS"," All standard SQL commands can be used"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are true statements? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Reference data types can be used to define the data type of the data element."," The technical attributes of the data element can be defined by a domain, that is, the data type, the field length, and the number of decimal places."," You can also select predefined data types to define the data type of the data element."," Field labels are defined for the domain."],correct:[0, 1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Your selection screen can be modified at which event? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" AT SELECTION-SCREEN OUTPUT"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN ON <field_name>"," AT SELECTION-SCREEN"," None of the above"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data element property do you set so that the system logs changes to the content of fields with this data element? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["Change document"," Input history"," PARAMETER ID"," Documentation"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement ends a screen sequence and starts from initial screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LEAVE TO SCREEN"," SET SCREEN 0"," LEAVE SCREEN"," CALL SCREEN"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: At most, how many menu items (including functions, separators and sub- menus) can a menu have on the screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above"," 10"," 20","15"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you add fields to an SAP-delivered transparent table without modification? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Define a structure containing the new fields and include it in the table definition."," Use the database utility to enhance the definition on the database directly."," Create an append structure containing the new fields."," Add the new fields to the table definition."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To create development classes"," To activate logging for transparent tables"," To maintain program translations"," To create lock objects"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When are the changes to the VB* table transferred to the database? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When the update work process is executed"," When the enqueue work process is executed"," When an update function module is executed"," When the main program is executed"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LxxxxUXX"," LxxxxF01","LxxxxTOP"," LxxxxO01"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can you change in the ABAP Debugger? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Definition of a structure"," Value of a reference variable"," Value of a constant"," Content of an internal table"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: SAP enhancements for customer exits are managed by which transaction? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Transaction CMOD"," Transaction SMOD"," Neither transaction listed here"," Application�CMOD"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The same text symbol can be used by other programs"," They facilitate multilingual functionality"," Then can store up to 256 characters"," They are easier to maintain than literals"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You use Unified Modelling language (UML) to design your classes. You want to describe the message exchange between objects. Which diagram can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Object diagram"," Component diagram"," Class diagram"," Sequence diagram"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you define local classes in ABAP, which syntactical sequence must you follow? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" PUBLIC SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PRIVATE SECTION"," The order is handled automatically."," PRIVATE SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PUBLIC SECTION"," The order doesn�t matter."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: With what can you simulate multiple inheritance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REDEFINITION"," INHERITING FROM"," INTERFACES"," CLASS CATEGORY"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which method of passing parameters is preferred for its performance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Pass by class"," Pass by value"," Pass by reference"," Pass by subclass"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you activate the program"," When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you save the program"," When you perform a syntax check on the program"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following types of SQL statements always bypass the SAP table buffers? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" SELECT SINGLE"," SELECT � UP TO 1 ROW"," SELECT SUM (sales)"," SELECT � INNER JOIN�"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the difference between a Unicode and non-Unicode program? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to flat data objects."," Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to character data objects."," Byte-type data objects cannot be assigned to character-type data objects."," Byte-type data objects cannot be compared to character-type data objects."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" None of the above."," An implicit enhancement point can be used to insert code in an SAP pro- gram and is always available to the customer."," Implicit enhancement options allow you to enhance interface parameters for function modules and methods without modifying the repository object."," Implicit enhancement can be used to enhance SAP objects developed prior to SAP NetWeaver 7.0."],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Each component has an interface; of what does this interface consist? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Interface context"," Interface view"," Data Container"," Interface controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you have to take into account before you decide to buffer a table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The data must always be read from the buffer"," The data read from the buffer may NOT be current"," The database server must allow table buffering"," The entire table content must be loaded into the table buffer"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Public event and protected handler"," Private event and private handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Private event and public handler"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The super class method is abstract","The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method","The superclass method is an instance method"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to add a field type CURR to a transparent table. What else must you do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Add a key fieldof type CUKY."," Create a new field CUKY as a pre-defined type.","Create a reference to a field of type CUKY."," Add a check table that contains a field of type CUKY."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Attachment to a field"," Import / export parameters"," Selection method"," Fixed values"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following must you do to be able to use a Business Add-in(BADI)? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Create the BADI implementation"," Modify the adapter class"," Activate the enhancement project"," Write code for methods"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When do you need to use the GROUP BY clause in the SELECT statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If you want to redefine the sequence of the columns in the result set"," If you want to use aggregate functions and all components in the field list are aggregate functions"," If you want to use ORDER BY to specify a sub-order"," If you want to use aggregate functions and at least one component in the field list is a column identifier"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Attachment to a field"," Import / export parameters"," Fixed values"," Selection method"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What will happen at runtime when accessing a buffered table? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" All SELECT statements will read data from the buffer."," Following an update to a buffered record, all table buffers in the system will be updated."," If data is read from the table buffer, the existing indexes are not used."," If table data is read using indexes, the table buffer will not be filled."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."," An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which hook method exists for all controller types? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" wddobeforenavigation( )"," wddoinit( )"," wddoonopen( )"," wddoonclose( )"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement ends a screen sequence and starts from initial screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SET SCREEN 0"," CALL SCREEN"," LEAVE SCREEN"," LEAVE TO SCREEN"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the default length of the type C data type? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 10","1"," 100"," 1�65535"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be exposed in the component interface of a Web dynpro component? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Custom methods of the component controller"," Context nodes of WINDOW controllers"," Standard hook methods of the component controller"," Public attributes of WINDOW controllers"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statement is true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A database LUW must be placed within an SAP LUW."," A database�LUW�cannot be placed within an SAP�LUW."," A database�LUW�must be placed without an SAP�LUW."," An SAP LUW must be placed within a database LUW."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How would you define a method of an ABAP class to prevent this method from being available in a subclass? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Protected"," Abstract"," Private"," Final"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: For which of the following purposes can you use the ABAP dictionary? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" To create lock objects"," To activate logging for transparent tables"," To maintain program translations"," To create development classes"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Public event and protected handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Private event and private handler"," Private event and public handler"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What scheduling technique is used by the ABAP debugger dispatcher for processing user requests? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Multiple Queue"," Round Robin"," First in , First out"," Shortest First"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" It can be used with any DBMS"," The application server buffer is NOT used"," Syntax is checked at design time"," All standard SQL commands can be used"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You display the content of an internal table using an ALV grid control. The content of the internal table changes during the program. Which CL_GUI_ALV_GRID class method can you use to display the changed content? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PAI"," SET_TABLE_FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PAI"," REFRESH_TABLE_DISPLAY in module PBO"," SET_TABLE _FOR_FIRST_DISPLAY in module PBO"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following items are used in a Web Dynpro Application to transport database data to the user interface? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Inbound plug"," Context node"," Supply function"," Interface controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can you find customer exists in an ABAP program? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Search for customer exists in the Repository Information System"," Search for �CALL CUSTOMER� in the program"," Search for �CL_EXTHANDLER� in the program."," Search for customer exists in the program documentation"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You use Unified Modelling language (UML) to design your classes. You want to describe the message exchange between objects. Which diagram can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Component diagram"," Class diagram"," Sequence diagram"," Object diagram"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following controller types can exist only once in a Web Dynpro component? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Window controller"," Component controller"," View controller"," Configuration controller"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When must a foreign key have domain equality? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Never"," Always"," For a check field"," For a text table"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: The data buffered on each application server� Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Is always the same."," Is does not the same."," Is never the same."," Depends on the users."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which property of the InputField UI element must be bound to a context attribute? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" value"," enable"," state"," visible"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you define local classes in ABAP, which syntactical sequence must you follow? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The order is handled automatically."," PUBLIC SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PRIVATE SECTION"," The order doesn�t matter."," PRIVATE SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PUBLIC SECTION"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What transactions can be used to carry out modification adjustments after a system upgrade? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Modification Adjustment: Dictionary Object Selection (Transaction SPDD) to adjust ABAP Dictionary objects"," Modification Adjustment: Object Selection (Transaction SPAU) to adjust ABAP Repository objects"," Object Navigator (Transaction SPAU_ENH) to adjust ABAP Dictionary objects"," Spool Administration: Initial Screen (Transaction SPAD) to adjust ABAP Repository objects"],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to display a dialog box in your ABAP program. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SET SCREEN 200."," CALL SCREEN 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," WINDOW 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," CALL SCREEN 200."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: In a subclass, you want to redefine a method of the super class. Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" The subclass method has same visibility as the super class method"," The subclass method has a lower visibility than the super class method"," The super class method is abstract"," The superclass method is an instance method"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" LxxxxF01"," LxxxxO01"," LxxxxUXX","LxxxxTOP"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When does the lifetime of a component controller begin and end? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" It begins the first time the Web Dynpro application is called at runtime and ends when the Web Dynpro application that called and instantiated the component ends."," It begins with the Web Dynpro component and ends with the Web Dynpro application that called it."," It ends the first time the Web�Dynpro�application is called at runtime and ends when the Web�Dynpro�application that called and�instantiated�the component ends."," It lasts from creating data within the controller to cover the whole period during which the component is in use."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which data type is allowed for the reference field of the Currency field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DEC"," CUKY"," CURR"," UNIT"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following can you use to enhance SAP standard tables and structures with fields? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Field exits"," Append structures"," Append search helps"," Customizing includes"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What data type you can create in the ABAP Dictionary? Please choose the correct answer ",Response: [" Structure"," Secondary index"," Type group"," Lock object"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements regarding search helps are true? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Help views can also be used for the selection method for search help."," You can use a database view for the search help selection method."," You can use a maintenance view for the search help selection method."," You can use transparent tables for the search help selection method."],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following includes are generated when you create a function group? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: ["LxxxxTOP"," LxxxxO01"," LxxxxF01"," LxxxxUXX"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the difference between a Unicode and non-Unicode program? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" Byte-type data objects cannot be compared to character-type data objects."," Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to character data objects."," Byte-type data objects cannot be assigned to character-type data objects."," Offset positioning in a Unicode structure is restricted to flat data objects."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be part of the signature of an instance constructor? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Import parameters"," Changing parameters"," Export parameters"," Exceptions"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: If you are using external debugging (debugging of HTTP and RFC requests,�which arrive in your ABAP system), what will the Debugger do? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Do not stop when the external breakpoint is reached."," May or may not stop, depending on external factors."," Never stop; external breakpoints operate on users other than your own."," Always stop when the external breakpoint is reached."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You define the value range in the data element."," A conversion routine can be assigned to a data element."," A conversion routine can be assigned to a domain."," You can enter documentation for the data element in the ABAP Dictionary."],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What scheduling technique is used by the ABAP debugger dispatcher for processing user requests? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Multiple Queue"," First in , First out"," Shortest First"," Round Robin"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to display a dialog box in your ABAP program. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" WINDOW 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," SET SCREEN 200."," CALL SCREEN 200 STARTING AT 5 5."," CALL SCREEN 200."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When you define local classes in ABAP, which syntactical sequence must you follow? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" PUBLIC SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PRIVATE SECTION"," The order is handled automatically."," PRIVATE SECTION, PROTECTED SECTION, PUBLIC SECTION"," The order doesn�t matter."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you embed a subscreen in a main screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use CALL SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen"," Use SET SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use SET SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which context object is the attribute LEAD_SELECTION_INDEX related? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Attribute"," Element"," Node"," Supply function"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to read data from two database tables A and B using a database join. Database table B contains details for data records stored in database table A. Your result should contain all combinations of matching rows from A and B plus all rows from A that do not have matching rows in B. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � FROM a INNER JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM a LEFT OUTER JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM b RIGHT OUTER JOIN a �"," SELECT � FROM a JOIN b �"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Can identify where program behavior may change"," Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view uses an inner join in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Candidate key view"," Help view"," Database view"," Maintenance view"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components belong to an elementary search help? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Attachment to a field"," Import / export parameters"," Selection method"," Fixed values"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How can Unicode checks be made? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Only in a Unicode system or as part of a conversion to a Unicode system"," In any system (after release 6.10) by specifying the program has Unicode checks active"," Cannot be enforced"," By running Transaction UCCHECK"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What happens when an authorization check fails? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" A type E message is displayed."," The program is terminated."," The system field SY-SUBRC is set to a value other than zero."," A CX_AUTH_FAILED type exception is raised."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are writing a function module that will be called from external system via remote function call (RFC). How do you report an error back to the external caller? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Write the error data into a CHANGING parameters passed by value."," Write the error data into an EXPORTING parameters passed by reference."," Write the error data into TABLES parameters that is passed by reference."," Write the error data into a RECEIVING parameter that is passed by value."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to translate dynamic text in a web dynpro. From which abstract class should you inherit? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" CL_WD_COMPONENT_ASSISTANCE"," CL_WD_CONTEXT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_COMPONENT_SERVICES"," CL_WD_CONFIGURATION_MODEL"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is correct? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" None of the above."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT and PROCESS AFTER INPUT event blocks."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS BEFORE OUTPUT event block."," The screen attributes can be modified in the PROCESS AFTER INPUT event block."],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following is a true statement?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" An access key is required to modify SAP repository objects."," An access key is required to implement business add-ins."," An access key is required to enhance an SAP application using a user exit."," An access key is required to implement an implicit enhancement point."],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: When is a foreign key check performed on an input/output field? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a search is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a append search is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a check table is defined"," If the field refers to the dictionary field for which a value help is defined"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the Web Dynpro programming model is based on? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Business Server Pages (BSPs)"," Internet Transaction Server (ITS)"," Classic Dynpro programming"," Model View Controller (MVC)"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: With what can you simulate multiple inheritance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" INTERFACES"," CLASS CATEGORY"," REDEFINITION"," INHERITING FROM"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."," The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."," The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How many kinds of internal tables are supported in the ABAP language? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 5"," 1"," 2","3"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following rules must you follow when creating subscreens? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Subscreens can call other subscreens."," Subscreens CANNOT have a field of type OK."," Subscreens CANNOT have an AT EXIT-COMMAND module."," Subscreens can have a dialog module containing SET PF-STATUS."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you use a sorted internal table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" You need to specify a key in the table declaration"," You use APPEND to insert records at the correct position"," You can resort the table with SORT"," You can read the records by index or key"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following transactions can you use to define transparent tables? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SE38"," SE11"," SE16N"," SM37"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following regarding search helps is a true statement? Please select all the correct answers that apply. ",Response: [" The text table for the selection method is automatically populated if the text table is attached to the database table being used as the selection method."," The SPos parameter defines the position of the input field on the dialog screen."," The interface for the search help is defined by the IMP (import) and EXP (export) flag of the search help parameter."," The LPos parameter defines the position of the search help parameter in the search hit list."],correct:[0, 1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You want to read data from two database tables A and B using a database join. Database table B contains details for data records stored in database table A. Your result should contain all combinations of matching rows from A and B plus all rows from A that do not have matching rows in B. Which statement do you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SELECT � FROM a JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM a LEFT OUTER JOIN b �"," SELECT � FROM b RIGHT OUTER JOIN a �"," SELECT � FROM a INNER JOIN b �"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following conditions must be fulfilled when using a GROUP BY clause in a SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" All fields in the SELECT clause that are not part of an aggregate function must be listed after GROUP BY."," The table in the FROM clause must be a transparent table."," The SELECT statement must also have a WHERE clause."," The fields after GROUP BY must have a character type."],correct:[0, 1]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the prerequisites when creating an append structure for a standard SAP table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The enhancement category of the table is NOT set to �Not enhacable�"," The table must be copied before the append structure can be created"," The table cannot have any fields of type FLTP"," The fields in the append structure should star with YY or ZZ"],correct:[0, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When would you call the RFC function module synchronously? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" During interactive communication"," During two-way communication"," During queue processing"," During unidirectional communication"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which method of passing parameters is preferred for its performance? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Pass by value"," Pass by class"," Pass by subclass"," Pass by reference"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of defining texts symbols in executable programs? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Then can store up to 256 characters"," They facilitate multilingual functionality"," The same text symbol can be used by other programs"," They are easier to maintain than literals"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You are making changes to a program that already has a transaction code linked to it. Your colleague is testing the transaction in your development system. At what point can the changed version of the program be tested? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" When you release the transport requests for the program"," When you perform a syntax check on the program"," When you activate the program"," When you save the program"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which statements about ABAP are true? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Each statement cannot begin with a keyword."," Each statement must begin with a keyword."," ABAP keywords and additions must be in uppercase."," Each statement must end with a period."],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What can be part of the signature of an instance constructor? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Exceptions"," Export parameters"," Import parameters"," Changing parameters"],correct:[0, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you add fields to an SAP-delivered transparent table without modification? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Create an append structure containing the new fields."," Use the database utility to enhance the definition on the database directly."," Add the new fields to the table definition."," Define a structure containing the new fields and include it in the table definition."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Dynpros can be placed in which program types?� There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Class pools"," Module pools"," Executables"," Function groups"],correct:[1, 2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do you need to consider when creating a secondary index on a table? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" The index can be created for specific database systems only"," The index must always be unique"," The most frequently selected fields should be at the first positions in the index"," The table will be updated more quickly if you create more indexes"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: To which context object is the attribute LEAD_SELECTION_INDEX related? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Attribute"," Element"," Node"," Supply function"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are some of the advantages of using OPEN SQL? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" It can be used with any DBMS"," The application server buffer is NOT used"," All standard SQL commands can be used"," Syntax is checked at design time"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: When do you need to use the GROUP BY clause in the SELECT statement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" If you want to use aggregate functions and at least one component in the field list is a column identifier"," If you want to use ORDER BY to specify a sub-order"," If you want to redefine the sequence of the columns in the result set"," If you want to use aggregate functions and all components in the field list are aggregate functions"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Where can you set the GUI status and the GUI title for a classical screen (dynpro)? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" In the attributes of the screen"," In the properties of the related header UI element"," In a module called from PBO of the screen"," In a module called from PAI of the screen"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which rules do you have to consider when working with pooled tables? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" An append structure can be created"," All fields can be used in indexes"," Only key fields should be used in WHERE condition"," Only key fields should be used in ORDER BY clauses"],correct:[2, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following statements are true?� There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" You define the value range in the data element."," A conversion routine can be assigned to a domain."," You can enter documentation for the data element in the ABAP Dictionary."," A conversion routine can be assigned to a data element."],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What do global types and local types have in common? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Field labels"," Technical information"," Documentation"," Search help"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You use Unified Modelling language (UML) to design your classes. You want to describe the message exchange between objects. Which diagram can you use? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Class diagram"," Object diagram"," Sequence diagram"," Component diagram"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How do you embed a subscreen in a main screen? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Use SET SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."," Use CALL SUBSCREEN in a PBO module of the main screen"," Use SET SUBSCREEN in the flow logic of the main screen."],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which ABAP statement can make an element visible that you statically defined as invisible? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 0"," SCREEN-INVISIBLE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 1"," SCREEN-ACTIVE = 0"],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the following are valid combinations of event visibility and handler method visibility? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Private event and public handler"," Private event and private handler"," Protected event and public handler"," Public event and protected handler"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What does the enhancement category for a database table or structure do? There are 3 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" Specifies the types of changes that can be made to the structure"," Can produce warnings at incompatible points for the structure"," Makes a table Unicode-compliant"," Can identify where program behavior may change"],correct:[0, 1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: How many kinds of internal tables are supported in the ABAP language? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 2"," 1"," 5","3"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: What is the allowed length of the ABAP Dictionary data type DF34_RAW? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" The allowed length is 34 digits."," The allowed length is between 0 and 33 digits."," The allowed length is between 1 and 34 digits."," The allowed length is between 1 and 31 digits."],correct:[0]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which type of view uses an inner join in a search help? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Help view"," Candidate key view"," Database view"," Maintenance view"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: How many work areas are available in the Debugger? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" 9"," 7"," 12"," 15"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which components of the class can be accessed in the implementation of a static method in that class? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" Instance attributes"," Types"," Constants"," All events"],correct:[1, 2]}	,
{Question: "Question: What are the advantages of creating a database view to implement a join, instead of formulating the join directly in an Open SQL SELECT statement? There are 2 correct answers to this question ",Response: [" An outer join can only be implemented in a database view"," A database view can be reused in other programs"," A secondary index can be created for a database view"," A database view can be buffered"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: You have implemented a class CL_CUSTOMER in which you defined a private attribute. From where can you access this attribute directly? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" From all methods of all subclasses of CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of a class to which CL_CUSTOMER grants friendship"," From any program using the class CL_CUSTOMER"," From all methods of the class CL_CUSTOMER"],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: SAP enhancements for customer exits are managed by which transaction? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" Application�CMOD"," Transaction CMOD"," Transaction SMOD"," Neither transaction listed here"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: In the CALL CUSTOMER-FUNCTION 'nnn' statement, nnn is a three-digit number�used in SAP programs for which of the following types of enhancement? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" New BAdIs"," Customer exits"," Business add-ins"," User exits"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: Table A and table B are partially buffered. Which of the following SELECT statements always access the database? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" SELECT a b FROM table A INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF TABLE lt_AB"," SELECT SINGLE FOR UPDATE a b FROM table A INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF ls_A WHERE c EQ �1234�."," SELECT SINGLE CLIENT SPECIFIED a b FROM table A  INTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF�ls_AB."," SELECT a b c d FROM table A JOIN table B ON table A~a�EQ�table B~eINTO CORRESPONDING FIELDS OF TABLE�lt_A_B."],correct:[1, 3]}	,
{Question: "Question: The following piece of code is used: DATA: def TYPE abc, Ghi LIKE xyz. Which of the four elements are data types and which are data objects? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" abc�- data type //  def,�ghi ,xyz - data objects"," abc,�xyz�- data type //  def,�ghi�- data objects"," def,�ghi�- data objects //  abc,�xyz�- data type or data object"," abc�- data type // def,�ghi�- data objects //  xyz�- data type or data objects"],correct:[3]}	,
{Question: "Question: Which of the elementary data types is deep? Please choose the correct answer. ",Response: [" DECFLOAT34"," XSTRING"," N"," X"],correct:[1]}	,
{Question: "Question: You enhance an SAP standard global class by defining a post-method for an SAP method. The original SAP method has an EXPORT parameter named PARM1. Which parameters does the post-method have? Please choose the correct answer ",Response: [" An OMPORT parameter named PARM1"," An EXPORT parameter named PARM1"," A CHANGING parameter named PARM1"," A RETURNING parameter named PARM1"],correct:[2]}	,
{Question: "Question: Is it possible to have multiple active implementations of business add-ins at a time? There are 2 correct answers to this question. ",Response: [" It can have multiple active implementations if the Multiple use checkbox is selected."," It can have a multiple active implementation."," It can have multiple implementations if the Filter-Depend. checkbox is selected."," It cannot have a multiple active implementation."],correct:[0, 2]}
];

export default quiz;